<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Overcome with Christ</title>
        <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com</link>
        <description>John 16:33</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 21:26:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Overcome with Christ</title>
            <url>https://overcomewithchrist.com/logo-icon.png</url>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2023, Overcome with Christ</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Power of Forgiveness ]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/the-power-of-forgiveness</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/the-power-of-forgiveness</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Holding grudges and being bitter only deteriorates you. Half the time the other person might not even know that they did you wrong, or think that they need to apologize.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Make allowance for each other’s faults, and forgive anyone who offends you. Remember, the Lord forgave you, so you must forgive others.” ‭‭<br>
<cite> Colossians‬ ‭3‬:‭13‬ ‭NLT‬‬</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>You probably already know that forgiving others is more for yourself than for the other person. Holding grudges and being bitter only deteriorates you. Half the time the other person might not even know that they did you wrong, or think that they need to apologize. So, to keep yourself from being bitter you forgive the other person.</p>
<p>Did you know, the same forgiveness you need to give to others, you should also extend to yourself? The same way you don’t want to be bitter towards others, you shouldn’t be bitter towards yourself. Maybe the reason you can’t forgive others is because you never learned to forgive yourself.</p>
<p>Recently I went through a lot of emotional ups and down with an individual. It took a lot for me to forgive them. But then I found that even though I told myself I forgive them, I still felt bitter about the whole situation. But the bitterness was pointed at myself. The situation was difficult because I couldn’t forgive myself for my own guilt.</p>
<p>I realized this after attending a leaders conference, and on the last day of that conference, I accepted the mercy of Christ, and forgave myself for all that I felt I did wrong concerning the situation I was bitter about. After I forgave myself, I found that I no longer was holding on to something that should have been dead already, and I was no longer holding myself back from being able to serve Christ fully again.</p>
<p>It’s good to extend to others the same mercy you extend to yourself. But if you find you’re harder on yourself than you are to others, then extend the same grace you do to others to yourself. You’re not greater than God the Father that you should harbor unforgiveness towards anybody, yourself included. Especially since He gave his only Son for you that you may enter into his eternal mercy.</p>
<p>So, if you’re harboring any unforgiveness right now, I challenge you to let go of it and break free from those shackles.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Lay aside bitter words, temper tantrums, revenge, profanity, and insults. But instead be kind and affectionate toward one another. Has God graciously forgiven you? Then graciously forgive one another in the depths of Christ’s love.” ‭‭</p>
<p><cite>Ephesians‬ ‭4‬:‭31‬-‭32‬ ‭TPT‬‬</cite></p>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685947837/blog/pexels-alleksana-4271937.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Things I learned about relationships]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/things-i-learned-about-relationships</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/things-i-learned-about-relationships</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’ve never really understood why many people feel like they are incomplete if they don’t get married.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The topic of marriage has always been a controversial topic for me. I’ve never really understood why many people feel like they are incomplete if they don’t get married.</p>
<p>In pursuit of answers, I’ve asked a lot of my friends about it, I’ve observed different dynamics in marriages, and I’ve tried to see what the Bible says about marriage.</p>
<p>In my rebelliousness towards marriage, I would alway stick to and meditate on Paul’s recommendation to not get married, or get married to sooth “burning passion” as he calls it. Or even Jesus’ own words about how some people choose to or are born to be eunuchs, and how there’s no marriage in heaven.</p>
<p>But recently, after meditating on the topic and with a little more openness to the concept of marriage, I’ve learned that there is a purpose in marriage. While everyone can create their purpose, God has also given us a purpose for marriage.</p>
<p>After speaking with my Pastor and many of the leaders that I consider mentors, I’ve come to see that the purpose of marriage is not just to please ourselves but to increase the kingdom of God. Whether that’s through doing ministry together, or in creating a godly seed.</p>
<p>When God is truly in a marriage, the marriage will bring him glory, and will expand his kingdom. I’ve seen that the marriages where both couples are on one accord spiritually manage to overcome a lot more adversaries smoothly.</p>
<p>Upon meditating on these things further I’ve come to realize that dating is still annoying and borderline unnecessary; standards are important and so is faith in God that he will direct you to the right person; boundaries are very important and don’t have to make sense to others; and it’s a good thing to want to have a family because having a godly family is also a way to bring glory to God.</p>
<p>I’m always so grateful to have the Holy Spirit and a teachable heart and mind. I’ve grown so much by listening to him, and meditating on the word of God. Many things in this world don’t make sense, but I’m forever grateful to the Holy Spirit who sheds light on all my thoughts and doubts no matter how simple or complex.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/img_1641.jpeg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Signs and Wonders: How does God talk to people?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/signs-and-wonders-how-does-god-talk-to-people</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/signs-and-wonders-how-does-god-talk-to-people</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What are some of the ways God can communicated with a group of people or an individual? Let’s talk about it in this post.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, God works through visions, dreams and angels, but the other 90% of the time he works through ordinary people like you and me.</p>
<p>Read through the Bible, how many times did he send an angel? How many times did he talk to some through dreams? And when that happened, what was next? The person with that experience was the one to share the message.</p>
<p>So what am I trying to say? I’m simply pointing out that God works through people to reach people. Maybe instead of waiting for a dream, listen to your Pastor, or your Leaders, or your mentor, or your Christian friends. Instead of looking for a sign in random places, look for direction in known sources.</p>
<p>Here’s what I mean, God reached out to Moses through a burning bush, and then Moses reached out to the Israelites as the voice of God. God communicated with the prophets through visions and dreams, then the prophets went out to the people as the voice of God. Jesus resurrected in the presences of his disciples and many others, then the disciples went out and preached the Good News as the voice of God. Saul of Tarsus heard the voice of the Lord, then he became the voice of the Lord for the multitude of people he preached his message to and brought to Christ.</p>
<p>I am not however telling you to disregard the other methods, but more so encouraging you to believe in the people placed around you. As Paul said, do not consider yourself to be better than anyone (<a>Romans 13:3-4</a>, <a>Galatians 6:3</a> ).</p>
<p>Also, don’t think yourself so high and mighty that other people can’t correct you, guide you, or discipline you. God disciplined Balaam through a donkey, David through a prophet (Nathan), and Esther through her uncle (Mordecai).</p>
<p>Finally, be careful your thoughts towards the positions God has assigned people: specifically your Pastor. Remember what happened to Mariam when she rebelled towards Moses, To Eli’s family line because of his son’s misconduct in their priestly duties, and to King Saul because he did not seek out a prophet but consulted mediums instead. God really cares about the organizational structures he’s put in place, and would not that anyone should mock him in disregard to these things.</p>
<p>Yes, signs and wonders, dreams and visions, and angelic visitations happen, but those are more rare than another ordinary looking individual coming to you as the voice of God for that situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/5b104e4d-1ab4-44a3-8986-1349885e4503.png" length="0" type="image/png"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epicurean Paradox - Debunked]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/epicurean-paradox-debunked</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/epicurean-paradox-debunked</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I saw this Epicurean paradox flow chart somewhere, and they were so close to the actual answer.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometime last year, I came across the flow chart pictured below. They were so close to the answer, so I decided to give the explanation for the path I circled. Hopefully, this helps someone understand the plan of God. </p>
<img src='https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1680975125/paradox_uad73k.jpg' alt='Epicurean Paradux Flowchart' width="350px" height="400px" class="mx-auto"/>
<p>He did destroy Satan, when Jesus died and when to hell, he destroyed death and the grave, and he made a spectacle of all the demons and their cohorts (<a>Colossians 2:15</a>).</p>
<p>So currently Satan only has power over those who let him have that power. Right now, we still live in this world as is because God is being patient with people (<a>2 Peter 3:9</a>). He doesn’t want them to also be destroyed with Satan, so he’s giving them the opportunity to accept Jesus and be saved (like he gave people the opportunity to get on the arc with Noah before the flood).</p>
<p>God is merciful, he doesn’t want people to perish, but He does not want to force anyone to do his bidding either. He would rather they chose willingly to come to Him. He’s done everything already. It’s up to us to accept What he has done and wait patiently for the day that the new Earth and the new Jerusalem will be revealed for all of God's people to be able to live with God, in a recreated world without sin (<a>Revelations 21:1-4</a>).</p>
<p><b>So why create evil?</b></p>
<p>He didn’t create evil. Because God is good, where ever He is not, there is no good. So evil comes from the absence of God in or from something.</p>
<p> When God recreated the Earth, he gave dominion over it to Man (Adam). But Adam allowed Satan to take over that dominion when he listened to him and ate from the tree. At that point, man started hiding from God (because he realized his nakedness). And that separation from God made way for evil. Because without good (God), is evil. Just like without light is darkness.</p>
<p>The earth was void, chaotic, and absent of light until God hovered and brooded over it, and brought light, order, and filled it. (<a>Genesis 1-3</a>)</p>
<p><b>Did he not anticipate Adam would eat of the Fruit? after all he’s all-knowing.</b></p>
<p>He did, that’s why he made the plan for the sacrifice of Jesus. The plan for Jesus wasn’t an afterthought, He planned it from the beginning (<a>John 1:1</a>, <a>John 1:10</a>).</p>
<p>Rather than destroy everything and “start over” he decided to let everything play out. He holds all the pieces to the puzzle, and He decides how he wants to solve that puzzle. Does a clay pot ask its potter “Why did you make me”?</p>
<hr />
<p>What do you think of this explanation? Am I missing anything? Do you have any additional questions? Contact me and let me know. </p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-david-bartus-366791.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lessons Learned In My 20s]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/lessons-learned-in-my-20s</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/lessons-learned-in-my-20s</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[My Birthday just passed, and since I'm almost 30, I decided to do a little reflecting. Here are 10 things I learned in my almost 30 years of living.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe class="w-10/12 aspect-video mx-auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/x85P-a8KZzI" allow="encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>Some of the things I might say here may sound extreme, but I’m okay with that. In this lukewarm world, people who know what they want always seem extreme.
Today I am going to discuss 10 things I learned in my almost 3 decades of being alive. My birthday just passed and I’m only a couple of years from being 30, So I decided not was a good time to impart some wisdom to y’all and also reflect on some lessons learned, most of them the hard way.
Jumping right into it:</p>
<ol class="blog-list">
<li><b>There’s no point being fake, just be yourself</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
<li>There’s only one of you, so learn who you are and be that</li>
<li>It’s okay to standout sometimes, being different isn’t always bad</li>
<li>It’s easier to build on something genuine than to continue to figure out something fake </li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>Your friend circle is crucial</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
<li>Have friends that are genuine and that you can be genuine with</li>
<li>Have friends that keep you accountable</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>The world doesn’t revolve around you</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
   <li>It revolves around Christ</li>
   <li>Let your pride be in the Lord</li>
   <li>Life moves on</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>Don’t do business with unstable people</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
   <li>Either you do them a solid, or you say no</li>
   <li>Don’t mingle business relationships with friendships when the person has shown themselves to not be professional</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>You don’t have to feel guilty</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
   <li>Guilt is different from remorse</li>
   <li>God doesn’t make people feel guilty, the devil does</li>
   <li> Don’t do anything for people because you feel guilty, do it because you want to help and are able to help</li>
   <li>You’re not the only person who can help someone, so don’t feel pressured to help everyone</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>Emotional Intelligence is important</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
  <li>Otherwise people will be too quick to manipulate you</li>
  <li>You’ll have a hard time keeping any kind of relationship if you’re not able to assess your emotions properly</li>
  <li> Accept that emotions can sometimes be unreasonable, but necessary. They should be guiding factors but not decision-makers.</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>It’s okay to lose friends</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li>Not everyone that you are or were close to needs to continue to be in your life</li>
    <li>Some friendships are useful only for a season</li>
    <li>The Holy Spirit is a better friend than any person could be</li></ul>
 </li>
<li><b>It’s okay to have standards and set boundaries</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li> You respect yourself more when you can stand up for what you believe in.</li>
    <li>People also respect you more when they know you have respect for yourself</li>
   <li>People don’t need to understand the reason behind your boundaries, they just need to understand where you draw the line</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b>Dating for fun is a waste of time</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li>I don’t know why people enjoy heartbreak so much.</li>
    <li> Dating intentionally makes it easier to know when it’s time to move on.</li>
    <li>If you don’t know what you want, you could end up with what you don’t want.</li>
    <li> Giving someone a chance doesn’t have to result in dating. People can prove themselves in friendship</li></ul>
</li>
<li><b> You’re not responsible for people’s actions</b>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li>Ultimately people make their own choices</li>
    <li>You don’t have to be extra anything to get people to do xyz.</li>
    <li>People will show you who they are if you just watch.</li></ul>
</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/10.png" length="0" type="image/png"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Respect your body]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/respect-your-body</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/respect-your-body</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Many people have different ideas of what it means to respect one's self, but after talking with my friends, and meditating on it a bit this is what I found.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>For this is the will of God, <em>even</em> your sanctification, that ye should abstain from fornication:</p>
<cite>1 Thessalonians 4:3</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>Many people have different ideas of what it means to respect one's self, but after talking with my friends, and meditating on it a bit this is what I found. Body purity is not just pleasing to God, but it shows respect for yourself as an individual. Be mindful of how you let others treat you because it's a reflection of how you view yourself. </p>
<h5>Why is body Purity important?</h5>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li><b>The Lord cares about our bodies</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
        <li>Our bodies were not made for sexual immorality but for the Lord</li>
        <li>Our body is part of Christ</li>
        <li>You become one with whatever you join your body with</li>
        <li>1 Corinthians 6:13 - 17, 1 Thessalonians 4:3-5</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li><b>Sexual immorality affects the body the most</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
            <li>Our body is the temple of the Holy Spirit</li>
            <li>We don’t belong to ourselves; God bought us with a high price - the blood of Christ.</li>
            <li>Sexual immorality does not honor God.</li>
            <li>1 Corinthians 6:18 - 20, 2 Corinthians 7:1, Romans 12:1</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li><b>Keeps your inheritance from you</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
        <li>You can not tap into your inheritance when you’re joined with sin</li>
        <li>You are defiling yourself when you join yourself with something other than the Spirit of God.</li>
        <li>We were cleansed and should try to glorify God in all we do.</li>
        <li>1 Corinthians 6:9, Galatians 5:19-21, 2 Timothy 2:22, Ephesians 5:5</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
<h5>We have the grace to live a Godly live</h5>
<ul class="blog-list">
    <li><b>Through Christ, we’ve been given all we need to live a godly life</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
            <li>2 Peter 1:3, 1 Thessalonians 5:23-24</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li><b>But we also have to do our part with what we have been given</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
            <li>Hebrews 12:1, Romans 6:11-14, Galatians 5:13, Titus 2:12, Colossians 3:1-3</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
    <li><b>God is not the one tempting or “testing” us. He’s already overcome it all so that we also can overcome.</b>
        <ul class="blog-list">
            <li>James 1:13-14, Hebrews 4:15-16, Psalm 119:9,</li>
        </ul>
    </li>
</ul>
<h5>Prayer</h5>
<p>Lord, <br />Thank you for your word which is a shining light unto my feet. Thank you for the strength and the ability to follow your word, for in following your word I am living a higher and more fulfilled life. Thank you for your grace and mercy. I need your help oh Lord to remain pure for you. Help me to not defile your temple. I will meditate on your word daily, such that it will stay in my heart and strengthen me during the evil day. Holy Spirit thank you for showing me the correct way and opening the eyes of my understanding of the truth. To you belongs all the glory father God, forever and ever.</p>
<p>In Jesus' Name<br />Amen</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/girl-and-penguin-figurine-3274626.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Life-Long Battle]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/life-long-battle</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/life-long-battle</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently I experienced a pain episode that really shook me. So, as part of my recovery, I decided to share my battle and testimony.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe class="w-10/12 aspect-video mx-auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lkFmEcpKgcs" allow="encrypted-media; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>Hi, my name is Cyntia and I was born with Sickle Cell Disease. Sickle Cell is when your blood doesn't get enough oxygen so it's not always round. Because of this, it can get stuck which can cause immense pain.</p>
<p>For me, a pain crisis It's not just about the physical pain, but the mental, emotional and spiritual battles involved. Some episodes are more painful than others and the recovery time depends on the level of pain.</p>
<p>Recently, I just went through an especially painful pain crisis which really shook me. It made me question a lot of things. I felt like I could die. Everywhere hurt, my arms, my legs, my chest, and my lower abdomen. They usually ask about your pain level on a scale of 1 through 10 and each hurting area was a 10.</p>
<p>Some crises I can handle at home, but this one I couldn't. So I went to the ER, and then got admitted the same night. I hate the pain medication, it makes my mind so foggy. I hate being in a hospital bed, the endless questions and shots, and vital checks. But that's where I found myself, yet again.</p>
<p>As soon as I could manage without all the probing, I got discharged and took the rest of my recovery home. This video is part of that recovery process. I want to share my battle.</p>
<p>I felt so many negative emotions and had so many negative thoughts. I felt weak, so weak. I felt useless. I felt cursed, I felt like I was losing my faith. I felt like the pain would never stop. I felt like the angel of death was waiting for me.</p>
<p>Despite wanting to quit, I wasn't about to give up. I knew that in my weakness God was my strength. I knew that Jesus died for me, so I wasn't useless. I knew that Jesus also set me free from all bondage. And though my faith was shaken to its core, I wasn't about to let go of it. Finally, My life doesn't belong to me, but it belongs to Christ, so I can't let the angel of death take me.</p>
<p>I still believe I have divine health, so I speak over my body on top of taking medication. One of these days this vessel will comply with the word of God. God's grace is sufficient. I rejoice that In the testing of my faith comes patient endurance and the pain of this present moment doesn't compare to the glory that will be revealed in me. Crying May last through the night, but joy comes in the morning.</p>
<p>It's still hard though, especially with the pain still fresh in my mind but I will continue to work my faith. And like Job said, though he slay me, yet will I trust in him. After all, he is the author and finisher of my faith and he's not finished with me yet.</p>
<h5>Say this confession over your body:</h5>
<p>I have the life of God in me because the same spirit that raised Jesus from the dead is alive in me and revitalizes my mortal body. </p>
<p>From the crown of my head to the soles of my feet my health is perfected in Jesus' name. Every fiber of my being operates by the power of the spirit that lives in me. </p>
<p>I am the temple of God, and anything that defiles this temple is destroyed in Jesus' Name. </p>
<p>I cast out every demon of infirmity looking to take root within me in Jesus' Name. </p>
<p>I am sound, I'm strong, I am well, I am loved, I am free, I am full of health in Jesus' Name.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/life-long-battle.png" length="0" type="image/png"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is God a Genie?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/is-god-a-genie</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/is-god-a-genie</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Do you believe that God is supposed to answer all of your prayers according to your will? Let's think about this.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>"Though he slay me, yet will I trust in him…"</p>
<cite>Job 13:15 KJV</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>Sometimes we think we make a better god than the Almighty Himself. It is so easy to question his form of justice when it does not align with what the world has thought us to be justice. We also claim that He isn't fair or right when things don't go our way. When we do this, we are usually just whining, and not reflecting on who God is.</p>
<p>It's not God who is to conform to our idea of justice, love, sovereignty, mercy, etc. but, we that have to conform to His will (<a>Romans 12:2-3</a>). Our will and God's will do not align because God makes adjustments but because we make adjustments.</p>
<p>If God adjusts his will based on every individual, he would be a confused and directionless God. Since he would be different depending on who he is dealing with, but the Bible says in <a>Hebrews 13:8</a>, "He is the same yesterday, today and forever".</p>
<p>Additionally, <a>Acts 10:34</a> also states "Of a truth, I perceive that God is no respecter of persons…", meaning he doesn't show favoritism. It's not because of your status that God is supposed to incline his ear more towards you. That also means that regardless of who you are God is ready to listen to you.</p>
<p>Above all, God is God and it's up to you to get on his level. Thanks to Jesus and the Holy Spirit, that's a lot easier to do than one might think. If you take the time to humble yourself, stop whining, reach out to Him, and listen you will find that you have some adjustments to make, and those adjustments are all within your power to do.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"… He will rescue us from your power, Your Majesty. But even if he doesn’t, … we will never serve your gods or worship the gold statue you have set up.”</p>
<cite>Daniel 3:17-18 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-356079-1024x619.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hope - a poem]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/hope-a-poem</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/hope-a-poem</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hope can be such a dangerous feeling. But if placed in the right thing, it can be very rewarding. Here is a poem that I wrote; enjoy.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Who against hope believed in hope...</p>
<cite>Romans 4:18</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>I see you</p>
<p>Yes, I see you.</p>
<p>I see how you're crying out for help</p>
<p>With that smile on your face as you pass by,</p>
<p>But the eye contact is hard to supply</p>
<p>Because you know if they see you inside</p>
<p>They might get caught in your raging sea</p>
<p>And if they sink, then well, that makes two of you.</p>
<p>If they can't help then what is there left to do?</p>
<p>Hope, hope, hope...</p>
<p>it seems too dangerous to hope.</p>
<p>Or maybe it's actually too comfortable</p>
<p>To think that perchance you could actually be stable.</p>
<p>Maybe the sea won't calm down</p>
<p>Maybe the storm is here to stay</p>
<p>Maybe chaos is all there is.</p>
<p>So you think it's better to not hold on to anything that could make you sink.</p>
<p>But have you considered holding on to what could make you float?</p>
<p>Not just for a moment, but for eternity;</p>
<p>Jesus Christ, the one true God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-lay-low-4506159-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Faith without works is dead]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/faith-without-works-is-dead</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/faith-without-works-is-dead</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What does it mean to have faith and not put in the work?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Even so faith, if it hath not works, is dead, being alone</p>
<cite>James 2:17</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>You've read before in <a>James 2:17</a> that faith without works is dead. I want to take a moment and challenge your understanding of this verse.</p>
<p>When you believe or have faith in something, you usually act according to that faith. If you have faith that a chair will hold your weight, then you sit on that chair without a second thought. If you believe that your God shall supply all your needs according to His riches and glory in Jesus Christ (<a>Philippians 4:19</a>), then you should act accordingly. If you have faith that your God is more powerful than anything in this universe and if He is for you, then no one can be against you (<a>Romans 8:31</a>), then why do you worry about your enemies and situations? If you have faith that by seeking first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, all these things will be added onto you (<a>Matthew 6:33</a>), then why are you worried about food, clothes, or all the things that unbelievers worry about? If you believe you have the victory then why are you talking defeat? Act and speak accordingly because faith without works is dead!</p>
<p>So then what about the commandments that Jesus has given us? Well, we don't do those works because of faith, but out of love. Jesus said the one who loves him, does as he has commanded (<a>John 14:15</a>). Therefore, we love God, love our neighbors, and walk in righteousness because we love him (<a>1 John 4:19</a>). Let's not confuse actions done for love with works resulting from faith.</p>
<p>Have any questions or additions? Leave them in the comments below and let's have a discussion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/Faith-1024x576.png" length="0" type="image/png"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 Things to know about the Universe]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/3-things-to-know-about-the-universe</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/3-things-to-know-about-the-universe</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What can the universe do for you? Does it bring you good fortune, or get back at people on your behalf? Read on and find out what power the universe has.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The Son is the dazzling radiance of God’s splendor, the exact expression of God’s true nature—his mirror image! He holds the universe together and expands it by the mighty power of his spoken word...</p>
<cite>Hebrews 1:3 TPT</cite>
</blockquote>
<h5>It was created by God</h5>
<p><a>Genesis 1:1-2</a> explains to us that in the beginning, before we had any concept of time, God created the heavens and the earth. This means that God is greater than the universe. If the universe is a huge and ever-expanding entity, and God created it, how much bigger is God than the universe? </p>
<h5>It's only a location</h5>
<p>The heavens isn't a being, and neither does it have intelligence. It only has laws and principles set by God Almighty. Including orbital patterns, gravity, separation of land and water, etc. So it can't grant or take away anything from you, or for you. Neither can it hear prayers and answer them. Actually, the heavens also praise God (<a>Psalm 148:3-5</a>).</p>
<p>In fact, God instructs that we do not look towards the cosmos and start worshiping it (<a>Deuteronomy 4:19</a>). How can we leave the creator to go worship his creation (<a>Isaiah 47:13</a>)? Don't you know by worshiping the creator, you also glorify His creation?</p>
<h5>It will be replaced</h5>
<p>On the day of judgment, there will be no room for this current earth and its surrounding heavens: its atmosphere and the current universe (<a>Revelation 20:11</a>). This universe and earth will disappear, and a new universe and earth will be brought down by the Lord almighty (<a>2 Peter 3:13</a>, <a>Revelation 21:1-2</a>). So, if you're looking to the universe for guidance, help, or counsel, know that you are relying on something that will pass away. Besides, there is something greater than the universe: Jesus Christ, the Son of God.</p>
<p>Have anything to add on the topic? Leave a comment below and let's have a discussion. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/salvation.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Not Alone]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/not-alone</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/not-alone</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[There will come a time when you will feel like you are alone in your belief. But you're not the only one who's felt that way.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Yet I will preserve 7,000 others in Israel who have never bowed down to Baal or kissed him!””</p>
<cite>1 Kings 19:18 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>As a Christian there will come a time when you will feel like you are alone in your belief. Like the whole world is against you or just doesn't get it. But you are not alone, not just because you have the Holy Spirit, but because there are others who also have that same spirit.</p>
<p>Remember Samuel when he fled from Jezebel and complained to God about how he was the only prophet left that still stood for God. Just for God to tell him that there are seven thousand other people who haven't yet bowed for Jezebel.</p>
<p>Sometimes it might feel like we are the only ones walking the narrow road, but I'm here to tell you, you are not alone! Keep going, keep standing firm, and know that others are fighting alongside with you.</p>
<p>Have any testimonies to share on this? Let's encourage each other in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-luis-fernandes-2422854-1024x680.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One way to examine your faith]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/one-way-to-examine-your-faith</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/one-way-to-examine-your-faith</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Sometimes it's good to take a moment to examine your faith and where it lies. Where does your faith lie?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Could you be tortured over what you believe in and still stick with your belief?
</p>
<p>
I think about this sometimes and I don’t like imagining being tortured, but even more, I hate the idea of denying Christ for comfort. Yet, it’s something I find myself doing oftentimes. For example, not telling someone about Christ because I don’t want them to think adversely of me. Or even not giving towards the Gospel because I am saving up for some worldly comfort.
</p>
<p>
Could you be like Daniel, Shadrack, Meshack, Abendigo, Jeremiah, Isaiah, the Apostles, Stephan, Or even Jesus himself? Could you suffer those things and still say, “yet my God is faithful”? Do you believe in God just for the worldly comforts that He might bring? Or are you laying up your treasures in heaven where nothing can get to it and destroy it? Do you seek worldly praise? Or do you wholeheartedly seek God's praises? These are some questions I often ask myself and challenge you to ask yourself as well.
</p>
<h5>Prayer</h5>
<p>
Oh Lord, I pray that we, as your dear children, never take what you have done lightly! I pray that we may never take for granted all that you went through to give us this life that we live. I pray oh Lord that we would also pick up our crosses when and where needed. I declare this day that you reign and rule over my decisions, my mind, and my life. I rebuke all fleshly desires that war against the nature of the spirit you have given me. I declare that all my actions are working towards building your kingdom. Thank you for choosing me to help with your work. I give you all the praise, honor, and glory.
</p>
<p>
In Jesus’ Name, Amen.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-ismael-sanchez-2282000-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reduce your negative thoughts by doing this every day]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/reduce-your-negative-thoughts-by-doing-this-every-day</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/reduce-your-negative-thoughts-by-doing-this-every-day</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It can be difficult sometimes to stay calm when feeling anxious, depressed, or distressed. But if you do this regularly, you'll find yourself being more in control.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
How often do you find yourself thinking about something negative that either causes you to be depressed or anxious? I know I still do, though not as much as I used to. One thing that helps me is meditating on scripture. Because scripture is how I fight off the lies that come to my mind.
</p>
<p>
Meditating is ruminating on or muttering something to one's self until it permeates one's spirit. Meditation also means to premeditate on an image, to ponder on a topic for the purpose of putting it to practice. So the main point of meditating on scripture is to permeate our spirit with the word of God as well as to ponder his commands to put it into practice.
</p>
<p>
Now that we know what we mean when say meditate, how does one do it? First things first, you must know why you want to meditate. What is troubling you? Are you anxious, depressed, or distressed? Whatever it is, think of a verse that deals with it. If one doesn't come up right away, stay in silence for a few minutes or speak in tongues if you are able and let the Holy Spirit lead you to a verse. However, you can always do a web search to help you out.
</p>
<p>
Once you have a verse selected that deals with your situation, it's time to go through the different levels of meditation. The first step is to set aside some time, at least 30 minutes, each day to meditate. During that time you will start by pondering quietly on the verse or verses you selected. Read it to yourself, think about what it says, think about what it doesn't say, consider how it applies to you. As you do this, you will start to understand that verse more and new revelations will come to you on the character of God and what role you play.
</p>
<p>
After pondering on the verse it's time to start muttering it to yourself. Your lips weren't moving before, but they should be now as you recite the scriptures over and over to yourself. This process helps it reach your spirit, it helps you to take it to heart. Even if you don't remember all the words of the verse, you will remember the character of God revealed in the verse when you face similar situations.
</p>
<p>
Once you've fully accepted the verse or verses to your spirit, it's time to roar it out. By this, I don't just mean scream it, but saying it loudly, confidently with a note of victory! There is victory when you understand who God is, and what role you play because in Christ we are always more than conquerors (<a>Romans 8:37</a>), hallelujah! There is a reason why the Word of God is the only offensive weapon given to us in the full armor of God (<a>Ephesians 6:13-18</a>).
</p>
<p>
As you grow your repertoire of scriptures in your heart and on your lips, you find that you can easily identify a lie being planted in your mind vs. the truth of God. The devil comes to steal, to kill, and to destroy (<a>John 10:10</a>). So resist him and he will flee from you (<a>James 4:7</a>). How do you resist? The same way Jesus did in the wilderness, with scripture (<a>Matthew 4:1-11</a>)!
</p>
<p>
Check out my previous post <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/renewal-of-the-mind">Renewal of the Mind</a> for more on this. Also, let me know if you're interested in me providing some (more) scriptures that I like to go to for certain thoughts! Stay encouraged, and keep overcoming!
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Study this Book of Instruction continually. Meditate on it day and night so you will be sure to obey everything written in it. Only then will you prosper and succeed in all you do.</p>
<cite>Joshua 1:8</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-lay-low-4506159-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Must Confess!]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-must-confess</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-must-confess</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[What's the difference between confessing our sins and confessing Christ?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Last month I committed to memory 1 John chapter 1 in the King James Version. As I was meditating on this chapter, I received so many revelations and wanted to share some parts of it. As you read this, keep in mind who John is addressing; babes in the faith.
</p>
<p>
Salvation starts with confessing Jesus Christ (<a>Romans 10:9-10</a>). Confessing Christ comes as a result of understanding where we stand, who Christ is, and what Christ has done. One thing that happens is we are translated from darkness to light, in other words, we start walking in the light. <a>1 John 1:7</a> says “But if we walk in the light as God is in the light then we have fellowship one with another and the blood of Christ cleanses us from sin”.
</p>
<p>
Notice it says sin as singular and a noun, and not sins as plural and a verb. This shows that we are changed, we no longer have a sin nature. We have been cleansed from sin which we were a slave to. Sin is defined as disobedience (to God) or lawlessness in <a>1 John 3:4</a>, so we are cleansed of our disobedient nature, cleanses of our lawlessness. John then continues in verse 8 "if we say we have not sinned we deceive ourselves and the truth is not in us". If we haven’t confessed Christ then we would be deceiving ourselves to say we have not sinned, after all, because of Adam's disobedience we are slaves to sin until we are set free of it.
</p>
<p>
Another thing that happens when we confess Christ is we are confessing our sins because we acknowledge that we were living in lawlessness. By declaring that we need Christ as Lord and savior we declare our repentance, thereby confessing that we have been in sin. <a>1 John 1:9</a> says "if we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and cleanse us from all unrighteousness". Glory to God, what a gracious God he is! Not only does he forgive us for our disobedience, but He cleanses us from all unrighteousness! No wonder Paul says "Therefore if any man be in Christ, he is a new creature: old things are passed away; behold, all things are become new" (<a>2 Corinthians 5:17</a>)!
</p>
<p>
The first chapter finishes at verse 10 with "if we say we have not sinned, we make him a liar and his word is not in us". Anyone who isn't born again is calling Christ a liar if they say they have not sinned, which makes sense that his word is not in them.
</p>
<p>
Based on <a>1 John chapter 1</a> anyone who isn't in Christ is walking in darkness, doesn't have the truth in them, and the word is not in them. But for all who confess Christ, 5 things follow them: they walk in the light as God is in the light; they have fellowship with the Father and his Son, and the brethren; the blood of Jesus cleanses them from sin; Jesus forgives their sins and cleansed from all unrighteousness; their joy is filled.
</p>
<p>
There is so much information packed in the first chapter of 1 John alone. I tried to keep this short while still getting my point across. I'm so amazed at all that Christ has done, and truly he deserves all the honor, praise, and glory forever!
</p>
<p>
If you aren't born again what are you waiting for? Check out my post: <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/ready-to-claim-your-salvation">Ready to claim your salvation</a> to join the kingdom of God today! You may not get another chance.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you declare with your mouth, “Jesus is Lord,” and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. For it is with your heart that you believe and are justified, and it is with your mouth that you profess your faith and are saved.</p>
<cite>Romans 10:9-10</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-andrea-piacquadio-3761509-1024x768.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What does it mean to have life?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-does-it-mean-to-have-life</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-does-it-mean-to-have-life</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I had to sit down recently and think about what it means to have (a) life. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>In him was life; and the life was the light of men.</p>
<cite>John 1:4</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
What does it mean to have life? This is something that I recently started to think about after I found myself thinking “I have no life”. Of course, when I was saying that, I didn’t mean that I had no physical life, I thought of it, as most of the world does, as not going out and doing “fun” things. You know, those things the world has made us believe are the benchmarks of “having a life”. As I was thinking this, the Holy Spirit asked me: “so why am I here”? It really threw me for a loop, so I sat down and thought about it: what does it mean to have (a) life?
</p>
<p>
The first verse that popped into my mind was <a>1 John 5:12</a> which says; <em>He who has the Son has life, he who has not the Son has not life</em>. Then <a>Deuteronomy 39:19</a> followed suit: <em>I have set before you <b>life</b> and death… <b>chose life</b></em>. So I took a moment and meditated on this. Later as I was doing my daily Bible reading, other verses started sticking out to me, like <a>John 3:16</a>, <em>“…so that anyone who believes in him would not perish, but have <b>everlasting life</b>”</em>. And <a>John 14:6</a> <em>“.. I am the way, the truth, and <b>the LIFE</b>”</em>. Wow, I was really amazed at this revelation.
</p>
<p>
Why would I ever say I have no life? How could I so blatantly disregard the Holy Spirit that dwells within me and gives me life? How could I show so much disrespect to Him who has done so much for me? Before writing this, I did some research and came to find the term <b>Zoe (greek: zwhv)</b> which is pronounced <em>dzo-ay</em>. One of its definitions was; <em>life real and genuine, a life active and vigorous, devoted to God, blessed, in the portion even in this world of those who put their trust in Christ, but after the resurrection to be consummated by new accessions (among them a more perfect body), and to last for ever</em>. That is the life that Christ is! Not only that, but that is the life that Christ gives! And I have this life! Glory to God forevermore!
</p>
<p>
Never again will I declare such a lie as I have no life. If you are in Christ, I urge you to do the same! Speak truth about yourself, don’t repeat the lies of the enemy. If you are not in Christ, then I urge you to read my post Ready to claim your salvation? And give yourself to Christ so you also can gain this life!
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I came that they may have life, and have it in abundance [to the full, till it overflows].</p>
<cite>John 10:10</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-zino-bang-54536-1024x768.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marathon to Recovery]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/marathon-to-recovery</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/marathon-to-recovery</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[While going through my old Gmail, I found this old blog post I wrote on September 12, 2013. This was 8 years ago, and right at the beginning of my decision to put my trust in God.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
While going through my old Gmail, I found this entry I wrote on September 12, 2013. This was 8 years ago, and right at the beginning of my decision to put my trust in God. I am always amazed and encouraged by my own journey. I truly am my biggest testimony. I hope you are blessed by the article as I was when I re-read it.
</p>
<hr />
<p>
Falling is always easier than getting back up. What with the constant downward push of gravity. But as Newton's Law of Enteria states: <em>a body at rest stays at rest and a body in motion stays in motion <b>UNLESS</b> acted upon by an outside force.</em>
</p>
<p>
Once you've hit rock bottom you're likely to just stop falling and lay there. And That's what I've been doing for the longest time: laying there at rock bottom. Not knowing where to go, who to turn to, what to do.. and frankly I still pretty much kind of don't. People aren't exactly the most dependable when you need them the most. So who can you put your trust into? Who can you go to so you can get that outside force that will push you in the right direction?
</p>
<p>
The answers to these questions are different for everyone, but for me, I've decided to put my trust in God. Because the way I see it, he's a lot more dependable than any human will probably ever be. You can talk to him whenever you want (even if you're not certain he's listening), and as you begin to just have that trust, and have that "someone" to talk to, you find <em><b>HOPE</b></em>.
</p>
<p>
Now hope can be very dangerous if not used correctly. Hope is the difference between how you will continue to live your life. Once you lose hope, you've lost pretty much everything. And let me tell you, I had lost all sorts of hope. I had no faith because it felt like my hopes were just always being crushed. But then I figured out that maybe, just <em>maybe</em> I was placing my hope in the wrong things. <em>Maybe</em>, if I pushed hard enough or long enough I could find the right place to put my hope in. Thanks to my <b>Family</b> and <b>Friends</b>, I found Hope in <b>God</b>.
I've decided to put my hope in God, to try and find my reason through him, to let him guide me so that I can stop being lost. I still have my doubts for now, but that's only natural because recovery isn't a <em>sprint</em>, it's a <em>marathon</em>.
</p>
<p>
Recovery is a journey into another world, a world you don't know if you can make it to. But if you push, and you try hard enough, you might just make it through (even with a couple of pit stops). It's easy to get discouraged at first; especially when you don't know what the future holds. Especially when your biggest fear is the future. But I know that if I keep trying, I will get somewhere worth being.
</p>
<p>
I don't quite see the light just yet, but I know I'm getting closer and closer to it. I can almost feel its warmth starting to radiate around me. I can feel the love of God just a little bit more because I can find hope sometimes even when things get rough. Plus I know things will get rough. Life only gets harder from here, so I need <em>His Unending Love</em> So that I may make it through this Journey.
</p>
<p>
I've still got a lot to work on. My eyes are always being opened, the light is steadily getting closer. But These things remain certain:
1.) The future is always uncertain
2.) God's love is everlasting, and his light shines when all else fails.
And like Tenth Avenue North sings in their song <span class="fbUnderline"><em><b>Worn</b></em></span>: I really want to see <b>Redemption </b>Win, cause I want to know a song can rise from the ashes of a broken life.
</p>
<hr />
<p>Can you remember where you were 8 years ago? How far has the Lord taken you? Share in the comments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-duong-nhan-1477538-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sometimes we need encouragement]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/sometimes-we-need-encouragement</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/sometimes-we-need-encouragement</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Sometimes reaching out to others about what you're going through can be very encouraging.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Last month, I was feeling a bit off and needed some encouragement. So, I asked in the slack bible study group we have at work if anyone had any words of encouragement for the day. I didn't get a reply until the end of the workday, but the reply gave me some perspective on things. Below is his reply.
</p>
<p>
<b>@Cyntia, my two cents</b>:
Today I was studying in John 18 where our Lord was on trial before His crucifixion. He endured utterly unreasonable questioning and treatment from the religious leaders who were supposed to be the defenders of the truth and of righteousness. The most shocking thing about this to me is the fact that He endured this leading up to and including the most shameful, abhorrent, painful death, and He did all of this WILLINGLY. Isaiah 53 talks about this very thing (He was pleased to crush Him, putting Him to grief). Certainly, it did not please God the Father to crush His Son for no good reason. It pleased Him to do so because His crushing of the Son meant our deliverance and freedom from the penalty of sin and reconciliation with God. What continues to shock me is that I know just how far I fall short of this kind of love, a love that caused our Lord to say, "The son of man did not come to be served but to serve and give His life a ransom for many." Just to think that the God of the universe served! utterly unworthy and evil people such as we are, and enemies of God at that (Romans 5), is an unimaginable grace that I know I give too little thought to. That is tremendously encouraging to me. Hope it is to you as well.
</p>
<p>
After reading this, it got me thinking about how much I am willing to do for Christ. Since Christ so willingly endured all this suffering, how much am I willing to endure for his sake? I find that most of the time I am asking for more without fully appreciating all that I already have. Am I fully using everything I've been given?
Christ has given us everything he has: yet, somehow, I continue to make mundane excuses as to why I'm too tired to do something and then throw in a mental note there somewhere that God will understand. If Jesus had that same mentality, where would we be?
</p>
<p>
I don't want to go on too much of a rant, so I will stop there. Share in the comments below something that Christ has called you to do that you have been hesitant to respond to. Why are you being hesitant? Let's have a discussion and encourage each other!
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-william-fortunato-6140466-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are my labels?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-are-my-labels</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-are-my-labels</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Everyone has a different take when it comes to the lgbtq+ community, here is my view on it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>But ye are a chosen generation, a royal priesthood, an holy nation, a peculiar people; that ye should shew forth the praises of him who hath called you out of darkness into his marvellous light</p>
<cite>1 Peter 2:9</cite></blockquote>
<p>
Everyone has a different take when it comes to the lgbtq+ community. What I need to figure out is when does love cross over to bowing down?
</p>
<p>
I understand the LGBT point of view. I used to identify as a hetero-romantic grey asexual. And if I knew about sex change and had access to it between the ages of thirteen and seventeen, I probably would have looked into doing it. But boy am I glad I didn’t have that option! I no longer feel the same way about these labels.
</p>
<p>
Not only were the labels confusing to keep up with, but they were annoying to explain and just increased the confusion within me. Now the only labels that matter to me are those that Christ has given me: king-priest, child of God, and joint-heir to the throne of God, amongst other things.
</p>
<p>
Do I think that males should go into a female bathroom because they feel they are a girl or vise versa? No. Do I think it’s okay for children to have access to sex-changing hormones? No. Do I believe my tax dollars should pay for children to change their sex? Absolutely not! Would I call a person by their preferred pronouns? Sure, but I honestly would prefer to use their name to avoid confusion. Do I think discrimination because of this is okay? No, as it just causes more division. Should we still preach to them as we would any other unsaved soul? Of course! The Holy Spirit deals with everyone individually.
</p>
<p>
In my opinion, a person's personality traits do not dictate their gender, but their sex does. It doesn’t matter to me if you are male and like pink, or enjoy cooking: or if you are female and like cars, gaming, etc. Your preferences won't change the role God gave you: and you do not have to change your preferences to play the role God gave you.
</p>
<p>
I still have people who second guess my sexuality because of how I dress, behave, etc. But after correcting them in love, I let it go. I know who I am, and the world cannot take that from me.
</p>
<p>
I pray that everyone would have clarity in the truth of who they are and that they would understand God does not make mistakes. I pray against the veil of deception that is causing confusion within people: may it be lifted, allowing freedom to come through truth.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-326576-1024x598.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are First Fruits?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-are-first-fruits</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-are-first-fruits</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Giving our first fruits is a way to honor and thank the Lord for all the provisions we received in the seasons past. It’s different from tithes in that it is not 10% of our income, and it only needs to be done annually.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>Honor the Lord with your wealth, with the firstfruits of all your crops; then your barns will be filled to overflowing and your vats will brim over with new wine.
<cite> Proverbs 3:9-10 </cite></blockquote>
<p>In <a>Leviticus 23:9-10</a>, God tells Moses to inform the people that they should bring him the first crops of their first harvest season in the promised land. In their obedience, they would remember that they were in the land that the Lord promised them.</p>
<p>Giving our first fruits is a way to honor and thank the Lord for all the provisions we received in the seasons past. It’s different from tithes in that it is not 10% of our income, and it only needs to be done annually; and it can also be done when God blesses us with a new job or business venture.</p>
<p>How much you give depends on how much you want to honor God with. It could be your first yearly paycheck, your first month's worth of income, your first paycheck from your new source of income, or any other amount you care to honor the Lord with. However, before deciding how much to give, I would strongly advise praying about it first; and when you give, be sure to give freely and not grudgingly.</p>
<h5>Why give first fruits?</h5>
<ul class="blog-list">
 	<li>Giving our first fruits means giving our best to God.</li>
 	<li>Giving our first fruits opens us up to the working of God in our lives.</li>
 	<li>Giving our first fruits shows where our priorities lie.</li>
 	<li>Giving our first fruits shows our obedience.</li>
</ul>
<p>When giving, whether in tithes, seeds, offerings, etc., don’t think about it as giving to the physical church, but as giving to the Lord. Your giving first and foremost shows your obedience and reverence for God. Your giving will be used for the expansion of the Kingdom of God. Remember, it all belongs to God (and you by inheritance).</p>
<p>This year I gave my first month's income as my first fruit sacrifice. It was tough because I kept thinking about all that I am saving towards. But then I had to remind myself that the Lord is my provider! I lack in nothing, neither do I want in anything because the Lord is my shepherd! I only have to stay obedient. As Psalm 91:1 says “He that dwelleth in the secret place of the most high, shall abide in the shadow of the almighty”. Therefore I declare: I abide in the shadow of the almighty!</p>
<p>I challenge you to give your first month's worth of income and see how your year pans out! Let me know in the comments if you accepted the challenge.</p>
<blockquote>The first of the ripe fruits and all the gifts brought to the Lord will go to the priests. The first batch of dough must also be given to the priests so the Lord will bless your homes.
<cite>Ezekiel 44:30</cite></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-ella-olsson-1458694-1024x819.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to start your new year strong]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-start-your-new-year-strong</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-start-your-new-year-strong</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As the year comes to an end, everyone starts to write goals and create ideas about how the next year will be.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
As the year comes to an end, everyone starts to write goals and create ideas about how the next year will be. Whether or not a year will be your year or just another year all depends on your mindset. When you keep yourself aligned with God's plan and purpose, every year is your year!
</p>
<h5>1. Fast</h5>
<p>
Fasting is an important spiritual activity. Decide on a fasting time and what you want in the coming year. Set aside time to read and study your Bible. Also, listen to messages or a single message on repeat as you are fasting; this will help align your mindset as you continue to the next steps.
</p>
<h5>2. Pray</h5>
<p>
While fasting, make sure you are also praying and asking the Lord for guidance. What does he have planned for you in the year to come? Which directions should you take? Which goals should you set? Where do you need to improve? What is the Lord's will for the world and how do you fit in it? Find out, and prepare yourself for the battles and victories that are coming.
</p>
<h5>3. Prophesy</h5>
<p>
As you pray, declare God's word into your life. Speak into your year. Declare all that you want to see. This helps shape your mindset on how the year should go. Speak that which the Spirit lays on your heart with power and conviction, then write it down for reference throughout the year. Be diligent in bringing these to your consciousness regularly throughout the year, so you know why you are doing what you are doing.
</p>
<p>
Every year has a purpose, especially as we draw closer to the Lord's return. Always do everything you can to match your will with God's will. When you do this, you will find Grace will be working in your life as you will not be frustrating the workings of the Spirit.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>And do not bring sorrow to God’s Holy Spirit by the way you live. Remember, he has identified you as his own, guaranteeing that you will be saved on the day of redemption.
</p>
<cite>Ephesians 4:30 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-karolina-grabowska-5716456-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Recap of the Year 2020]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/recap-of-the-year-2020</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/recap-of-the-year-2020</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[2020 was quite the year! This post is just a recap of all that happened to me and with me during the year 2020. Leave your comments and let me know how it was for you.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>2020 was quite the year! It was full of ups and downs for many but for me, it was full of joy and peace. This post is to give thanks to God for all he has done for me throughout this year. I have so many testimonies of what the Lord has done, but I will only name a few.</p>
<ul class="blog-list">
 	<li>I got a significant raise at the beginning of the year.</li>
 	<li>The Lord preserved me at my job when 28 people got let go, including my manager, mentor, and the only other junior in the office.</li>
 	<li>The Lord kept my family; I never received news of anyone in my immediate family getting Covid.</li>
 	<li>Even though my uncle contracted Covid after I spoke with him and we prayed, he fully recovered.</li>
 	<li>The title for the car I have been driving for practically 8 years now was switched over to me.</li>
 	<li>I lost 15lbs during the quarantine.</li>
 	<li>My prayer and fasting life has dramatically improved!</li>
 	<li>I started this impactful blog!</li>
 	<li>I renewed my lease without any rent increase.</li>
 	<li>The Lord informed me that my eyesight is restored!</li>
 	<li>I was able to bring 6 people into the Kingdom of God.</li>
 	<li>I was able to start a Bible study group that impacted the members.</li>
 	<li>I made an awesome new friend, and they greatly enriched my friend circle!</li>
 	<li>I never lacked anything that I needed during this year.</li>
 	<li>My relationship with God has improved drastically!</li>
</ul>
<p>The list goes on and on. I praise God for everything He has done. I thank him for the peace and joy that comes with my salvation. I thank him for who He is and for who He has made me. Words are not enough to express my immense gratitude! I exalt and worship His wonderful name. There is no other God as great, as powerful, and as loving as Jesus!</p>
<p>How did your 2020 go? Do you have any testimonies you would like to share? Do you need prayer? Let me know down in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-markus-winkler-4057655-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is Christianity]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-is-christianity</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-is-christianity</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Being a Christian is more than just going to church. It's a lifestyle, understanding, and spiritual renewal and development. Don't understand what I mean? Continue reading for more details.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Being a Christian is more than just going to church. It's a lifestyle, understanding, and spiritual renewal and development. Don't understand what I mean? Continue reading for more details.
</p>
<h5>1. Lifestyle</h5>
<p>
Being a Christian is a lifestyle. It's not something that you leave at church or the doorstep when you go out. It's something you do every day. The same way you wake up, breathe, and move is the same way you are a Christian. Everything you do should glorify Christ (<a>1 Corinthians 10:31</a>). The words you speak should reflect your heavenly father (<a>2 Timothy 2:16</a>). The decisions you make should have Christ and his kingdom in mind. The Holy Spirit should be more than just an experience, but also a counsel.
</p>
<h5>2. Understanding</h5>
<p>
Being a Christian is an understanding (<a>Ephesians 1:18-19</a>). You should know that Christ is who the Bible says He is. You should understand that He is the God of the living and not of the dead (<a>Matthew 22:32</a>). As you build your understanding of Christ, you build your understanding of who you are. When you understand that nothing is impossible to God and that he that is in you is greater than he that is in the world, the way you go about things changes. Faith is a stepping stone to understanding. If you have faith, then you are on your way to building your understanding.
</p>
<h5>3. Spiritual renewal and development</h5>
<p>
Being a Christian is a renewal and development of your spirit. When you got born again, a new spirit was given to you (<a>2 Corinthians 5:17</a>, <a>Ezekiel 36:26</a>). This new spirit will now need to be developed. Spiritual development comes through reading the Bible and knowing the character of God. It also comes through meditation and spending time in prayer with the Holy Spirit. Putting your faith into practice is how you show spiritual growth which causes things to change in your life (<a>James 1:22-25</a>).
</p>
<p>
Do not take what you have been given for granted. Your life should change once you are born again. It could change slowly or suddenly, but either way, there will be a change. Yield to the Holy Spirit because He now dwells in you. You are the temple of God so keep your temple holy (<a>1 Corinthians 3:16</a>). Know also that you still have free will, so choose to do godly things and not worldly things.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-356079-1024x619.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There is always something to pray about]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/there-is-always-something-to-pray-about</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/there-is-always-something-to-pray-about</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Saying "I won't pray today because I don't know what to pray about" is no longer acceptable. Lack of a reason to pray is not a reason to not pray...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>One day Jesus told his disciples a story to show that they should always pray and never give up.</p>
<cite>Luke 18:1</cite></blockquote>
<p>
One thing I struggle with sometimes is figuring out what to pray about. It can be hard to be disciplined in my prayer life. I used to think that I only needed to pray when I had something to ask of God. The Holy Spirit has shown me this mindset is quite flawed because there are so many things to pray about! Here are a few things to consider that can help to improve your prayer life.
</p>
<h3>1. Intercession</h3>
<p>
Putting our selfish desires aside, we can come to God to stand in the gap and intercede for the unsaved. These people could be family, friends, coworkers, or strangers. Intercession is when you pray on behalf of someone else.
Paul urged Timothy to pray for the unsaved and leaders in <a>1 Timothy 2:1-2</a>. God wants all who belong to him to come to him, and sometimes he needs someone to stand in the gap for their sake (<a>Ezekiel 22:30</a>). Paul also asks for intercessory prayer in <a>2 Thessalonians 3:1</a>. You will also find many places in the Epistles where either Paul is asking for intercessory prayer or is interceding for others in the church. Thus, we should also pray for our pastor(s), church, and fellow brethren in the Lord (<a>1 Thessalonians 5:25</a>, <a>Ephesians 6:18</a>, <a>Colossians 4:13</a>). Don't forget to pray for your enemies as well (<a>Matthew 5:44</a>, <a>Romans 12:14</a>).
</p>
<h3>2. World problems</h3>
<p>
There are many evils constantly taking place in the world that could use prayer. If you need some examples, look at the news; you will get plenty. Pray for things to improve.
Whether it's scandals, rape, racism, kidnapping, sex trafficking, the state of the country, or anything else, be the person to pray about it! Be the person to start noticing and bringing it to God. Then listen and watch as things begin to change around you. Watch your community improve. Who knows, maybe God can give you an idea of how you can get involved and help with the situation you are praying about.
</p>
<h3>3. Fellowship</h3>
<p>
Another option is seeking fellowship and intimacy with God. This prayer is not about asking God for anything other than his presence. The goal is to spend time with God, to seek His face, and to know his will.
When you fellowship with the Holy Spirit, you will find yourself feeling refreshed, strengthen, and comforted. You'll gain a deeper understanding of who your God is and what His plans are for you and the world. You will also gain a better understanding of who you are because you'll see Whose you are. To me, this is one of the most powerful reasons to pray.
</p>
<p>
These are things that I've learned I can always pray about. So saying "I won't pray today because I don't know what to pray about" is no longer acceptable. Lack of a reason to pray is not a reason to not pray.
If I pray regardless of these feelings, the Holy Spirit will bring fort things to pray about. This is why it's important to learn how to pray in the Spirit (<a>Romans 8:26</a>, <a>1 Corinthians 14:</a>).
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-suzy-hazelwood-1226398-1024x576.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My 2020 Fasting Journey]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/my-2020-fasting-journey</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/my-2020-fasting-journey</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[This year, I learned what it is to fast. Quarantine gave me the perfect opportunity to begin to learn how to have self-control when it comes to eating. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
I used to think that I would never be able to fast. The thought of giving up food for any amount of time was so wild to me. I barely had self-control enough to say no to seconds or thirds of most meals, no matter how full I felt. Even after eating way more than I needed, if my stomach growled at me funny, I would start thinking about what I should eat. Nevermind if it's only been 2 or 3 hours since I last stuffed myself.
</p>
<p>
This year, I learned what it is to fast. Around November last year, I decided that the new year would be a year of self-control for me; and I set a dietary restriction for myself. I limited my meat intake to birds and things that swim. The first thing I did during those last 2 months was work on becoming more conscious of what I ate. As part of the consciousness process, I thought about alternatives I could take that I didn't consider. This helped a lot because I was able to stop myself more easily when the new year came.
</p>
<p>
The reason for this specific self-control goal was two-fold: lose weight while expanding my meal pallet, and prove to myself that I can do all things through Christ. When we had to quarantine because of Covid, I thought to myself: "this will make fasting so much easier! Since I'm quarantined, I have control of my fridge and my meals, and I don't have to interact firsthand with people!" This helped a lot because it's hard to interact with people when all I can think about is how I can't eat! When fasting, Jesus said we're not supposed to show that we're fasting, so snapping at people was a no-no (<a>Matthew 6:16-18 </a>).
</p>
<p>
After being consistent in my fasting, I started to see the benefits of being able to control when and what I eat. I was doing 18hr fast with a 6hr eating window, between 1 pm and 6 pm. During my fasting times, my body felt lighter, I would have random spurts of energy, and I felt more focused while working. My times of prayer also were more focused (except during moments of weakness).
</p>
<p>
Since then, I've been able to offer myself as a living sacrifice more often to the Lord by being more open to the prompting of the Holy Spirit to fast. However, it's not always easy. Through it all, I've learned a lot about what I can do because of the abilities that Christ has given me through his Spirit. I've learned that I can practice self-control. I still love food, but I also love having a lighter body and a clearer mind.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-engin-akyurt-1907642-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Who you surround yourself with matters]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/who-you-surround-yourself-with-matters</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/who-you-surround-yourself-with-matters</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Your friend group is very important no matter who you are. They usually end up dictating the types of habits you build.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Keep company with the wise and you will become wise. If you make friends with stupid people, you will be ruined.</p>
<cite>Proverbs 13:20 (GNT)</cite></blockquote>
<p>
Your friend group is very important no matter who you are. They usually end up dictating the types of habits you build. The more you interact with them, the more you will start to reflect them in some way.
</p>
<p>
If you are surrounded by people who are toxic, you will find yourself developing toxic habits. Especially during moments when you're not feeling strong, or are at your best; moments where you need a mental break or emotional support which you may not be able to find. If you surround yourself with people with good character, you will find that you will also develop good character. During your moments of weakness, you will be empowered to do better, because you have good examples to follow.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As iron sharpens iron, so a friend sharpens a friend.</p>
<cite>Proverbs 27:17 (NLT)</cite></blockquote>
<p>
Having said that, who you are is who you will tend to attract, whether or not that's who you want to be. By this I mean, if you are more likely to be lazy, then you will find yourself around more people who are lazy. Even though you wish to be a hard worker, surrounding yourself with hard workers might feel threatening; especially if you're not ready to put in the work. So, work to be the person who you want to be, and you will see that the people who you start to attract will reflect that; expressly when mixed with prayer.
</p>
<p>
Throughout different seasons of my life, I have noticed that my friend group always matched and helped solidify who I was. While in school, I tended to befriend people who were like-minded and bore similar characteristics to me. Each of my friends held at least one characteristic that resembled me. Whether it was wanting to do well in school, or having some self-destructive tendencies.
</p>
<p>
I praise God I was able to find a church full of admirable people on my first try. This meant that as I developed new relationships in college, I was mainly surrounded by Christ-loving, God-fearing, authentic people. These qualities were really something I could look up to, and things that I really wanted to pick up on. I thank God for them often. I also thank God that he always took me out of toxic relationships even if I didn't really want to part from them. While it stung at first, it really helped me to grow, especially when I learned to not cling to these relationships.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wounds from a sincere friend are better than many kisses from an enemy.</p>
<cite>Proverbs 27:6 (NLT)</cite></blockquote>
<p>
All this to say, it's okay if God takes you out of certain relationships that meant a lot to you. He does it for your and their benefit. His plans for us are good, even when it hurts. When you start to change for Christ, the people you find yourself wanting to be around will also change. Additionally, the people who want to be around you will also change. It's bittersweet sometimes but if you let go and let God, you'll find yourself surrounded by amazing individuals who will help instill Christ-like values into your life. Pray that God brings you to these people, and open yourself to making new relationships, and closing others. It's not the end of the world, it's the beginning of your story of glory.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But now I am writing to you that you must not associate with anyone who claims to be a brother or sister but is sexually immoral or greedy, an idolater or slanderer, a drunkard or swindler. Do not even eat with such people.</p>
<cite>1 Corinthians 5:11(NIV)</cite></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-dennis-magati-862848-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Faith over fear]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/faith-over-fear</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/faith-over-fear</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[If faith is the evidence of things not seen, and the substance of things hoped for, then what is fear? Why should we make sure to continuously build our faith?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>For we walk by faith, not by sight.</p>
<cite>2 Corinthians 5:7</cite></blockquote>
<p>Hebrews 11 defines faith as: "The evidence of things not seen, and the substance of things hoped for". That means your faith brings to life the things you don't yet see, and it brings to existence the things you hope for. If you have faith that God will help you pay your bills, then you have evidence it will happen, without yet having the bill paid. With your faith, you bring now to reality, what you are hoping for. Hope can be defined as "a feeling of expectation and desire for a certain thing to happen". Therefore, you are bringing to reality your expectations and desires through your faith.</p>
<p>Now, the opposite of faith is fear. If you are fearful then you are taking the same principles of faith, but for your own downfall. If you are fearful that you will lose your house, then you are creating evidence that the devil has the power to ruin your current situation, and therefore you are bringing into your reality what your expectations are of your current situation.</p>
<p>Do not give opportunity to the devil (<a>Ephesians 4:27</a>), stand strong on the promises of God! How do you do that? The Bible says that faith come by hearing, and hearing by the word of God (<a>Romans 10:17</a>). So make time to read scripture, make time to listen to sermons, make feeding your spirit a priority over everything else. Then you will prove that the word is written in your heart. Let the word remain on your lips, so that you can bring light to all your situations (<a>Isaiah 59:21</a>)!</p>
<p>In everything you do, if you aren't doing it for the glory of God, then you are doing it for Satan. You're either for the Kingdom of God or against it, point-blank. The Bible says that Satan is the god of this world (<a>2 Corinthians 4:4</a>), so when we rely on the information and understanding that the world has to offer, we are opening our spirits to tainted truths and lies. This is why mind renewal is so important when we become born again. If you can spend 5hrs on YouTube or Netflix feeding your flesh, you should be able to spend that same amount of time doing something to feed your spirit and advance the kingdom of God. Besides, one has a better return on investment than the other when it comes to eternity.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>And it is impossible to please God without faith. Anyone who wants to come to him must believe that God exists and that he rewards those who sincerely seek him.</p>
<cite>Hebrews 11:6</cite></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/Faith-1024x576.png" length="0" type="image/png"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marriage: Thoughts on Courting vs Dating]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/marriage-thoughts-on-courting-vs-dating</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/marriage-thoughts-on-courting-vs-dating</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I have been thinking a lot lately about marriage.  I have especially been considering the difference between old-style courtship and modern-day dating. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been thinking a lot lately of marriage. I have especially been considering the difference between old-style courtship and modern-day dating.</p>
<p>The cambridge dictionary defines courtship as</p>
<blockquote>
<p>the period in which two people have a romantic relationship that often leads to marriage</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And dating as</p>
<blockquote>
<p>to regularly spend time with someone you have a romantic relationship with</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From that, I gather that while I can spend time with someone romantically, it doesn't mean that I'm planning to marry them. However, I can date someone I'm in courtship with.</p>
<p>In the world today, people don't really court, but they date. They spend time with an individual with no mutual intention of marriage involved. Dating is treated as a recreational activity; which can lead to destructive behaviors.</p>
<p>I've seen that when simply dating, it's usually just about being able to have that someone to fill the void; a void that really only Jesus can fill. Not to mention that if Jesus isn't at the center of both individuals lives then sin can easily take over since we end up right in the midst of temptation.</p>
<p>Unless both parties are willing to fight these temptations, then someone is going to either give in or leave. Which comes with many hurt feelings, egos, and pride that lead to the defaming of the other individual because of bitterness.</p>
<p>From now on, I would prefer to date in courtship rather than dating recreationally. Let our intentions be made known, and be clear. Let's get to know each other in a way where we realize that this could potentially be forever, til death do us part. Let's build each other up and see if we can actually make our relationship last. Let's learn about each other and decide if we're going to get through the good, the bad, and the ugly together. </p>
<p>At the end of the day, commitment is a decision that is made daily. Some days it might be easier than others, but it's can be demoralizing to want to stay committed to someone when you don't know if they see a future with you the same way you see a future with them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Love is patient and kind. Love is not jealous or boastful or proud or rude. It does not demand its own way. It is not irritable, and it keeps no record of being wronged.</p>
<cite>1 Corinthians 13:4-5 NLT</cite></blockquote>
<p>See my other post on relationship: <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/a-conversation-about-relationships/">A conversation about relationships</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-vjapratama-935789-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to make sharing the Gospel a little easier]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-make-sharing-the-gospel-a-little-easier</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-make-sharing-the-gospel-a-little-easier</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Bringing people to Christ can be a daunting task, but it's important to understand that it’s the Spirit within us that does most of the work. Once we understand that, here are other things we can do to help make the task a bit easier for us.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Bringing people to Christ can be a daunting task, but it's important to understand that it’s the Spirit within us that does most of the work. Once we understand that, here are other things we can do to help make the task a bit easier for us.
</p>
<h5>1. Pray</h5>
<p>
It’s always important to start with prayer. Pray for the infilling of the Holy Spirit and boldness. Pray for the salvation of the soul that you are going to touch and intercede for them before you go to speak to them. Prayer is the first and most important step, it preps you mentally for what you are trying to do and aligns you with God’s purpose.
</p>
<h5>2. Have something to give out</h5>
<p>
Once you are aligned spiritually with your task, it helps to have something to pass out. Having something like a church card, a daily devotional, a small bible or even a small informational booklet can help in giving you a reason to approach the person. It also allows you to have something to reference, especially if it’s a bible, booklet, or devotional. If the individual is receptive to the item, then strike up a conversation with them. Don’t be forceful if they don’t want to chat. Just wish time a good day, and continue on.
</p>
<h5>3. Have a couple questions in mind to ask</h5>
<p>
If they are receptive to the item, or maybe you're already in conversation with someone (without an item) it can help to have a couple of go-to questions that can bring Christ in. The question could be something like “who do you think Jesus is?” or “What do you think happens when you die?” or even “are you born again? Do you know what it means to be born again?”, then go from there. If they are already born again then great! If not, then this is your opportunity to explain, and maybe throw in some testimonies. Then lead them through the prayer of salvation if they accept and want to join the kingdom! Congratulate them for their new achievement and find a way to keep in touch with them.
</p>
<h5>4. Realize that they aren't rejecting you, but Jesus</h5>
<p>
If they don't want to hear it or are in a hurry, or sometimes even rude; try not to take it personally. They aren't rejecting you, but Jesus (<a href="#">Luke 10:16</a>). When you bring it up you are planting a seed (<a href="#">Matthew 13:1-23</a>, <a href="#">Mark 4:1-20</a>, and <a href="#">Luke 8:4-15</a>). But do not let rejection discourage you, just keep going cause God is with you. Remember you are going about your heavenly Father’s business.
</p>
<p>
This is a continuation of my previous post: <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-should-we-share-the-gospel-and-bring-people-to-christ/">Why should we share the Gospel and bring people to Christ?</a>
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-keira-burton-6146951-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why should we share the Gospel and bring people to Christ?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-should-we-share-the-gospel-and-bring-people-to-christ</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-should-we-share-the-gospel-and-bring-people-to-christ</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As Christians, it’s important that we share the word with others.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As Christians, it’s important that we share the word with others. It’s not just about sharing the word, but more importantly, getting people to give their life to Christ. Just in case you’re wondering why this is important, I have listed 3 reasons below.</p>
<h5>1. Jesus sent us on this mission</h5>
<p>In <a>Mark 16:15-16</a> and <a>Matthew 28:19-20</a> Jesus says to the disciples “go and make disciples of all the nations”. Going out and preaching the word to the world is the one mandate that Jesus has given all who follow him. Which lines up with loving your neighbor as yourself; since loving your neighbor also means not wanting them to stay in spiritual death nor be part of the second death. You can learn more about why salvation is needed in my previous post: <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-we-need-salvation/">Why we need salvation</a>.</p>
<h5>2. God wants everyone to know the truth</h5>
<p>In <a>John 15:22</a> Jesus explained to his disciples that it wouldn’t be fair for people to be judged if they didn’t get the chance to hear him speak. Thus, when we share the Gospel with people, we are giving them the opportunity to make their choice. God’s judgment then just becomes an affirmation of their choice. This also takes the responsibility off you since your part is done (<a>Ezekiel 33:7-9</a>, <a>Acts 18:6</a>).</p>
<p>In <a>1 Timothy 2:4-5</a>, Paul also lets us know that it is God’s will for everyone to be saved and know the truth. And the truth is that there is only one mediator who can reconcile God and humanity – the man Christ Jesus. Being a good person doesn’t give you spiritual life, being born again through Jesus does. Part of preaching the Gospel is just letting people know this simple truth. Some people will reject it, but Jesus already knows that.</p>
<h5>3. It will lead the way to Jesus’ return</h5>
<p><a>Matthew 24:14</a> lets us know that the end will come when the Gospel is heard by all nations. If you’re like me, and you’re ready for Jesus to come back already, then preach the Word! We have this responsibility, and when Jesus does come back, I want to be able to show that I did my best to bring his sheep back to him.</p>
<p>There are some things that are sometimes easier said than done and depending on your personality type, this could be one of them. Look out for a future post on how to make sharing the gospel a little easier. Hopefully, that will give you some good tips to help you put this into practice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-andrea-piacquadio-2672979-1024x662.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do you respond to sickness?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-do-you-respond-to-sickness</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-do-you-respond-to-sickness</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Infirmities are hard to deal with and everyone deals with them differently, but in all things, I know that God will bring me through it. Sickness doesn't rule me, Christ does]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was born into this world with sickle cell. For those of you who don't know what that it, it is a blood disease where blood is more prone to not getting enough oxygen. When that happens, instead of being nice and round so it can travel through my veins and capillaries smoothly, it takes the shape of a sickle. This c shape is pointy and not so smooth and can get stuck while traveling. Which causes immense pain in the area where the clog happens.</p>
<p>I’ve been to the hospital more times than I can count. I've had transfusions, surgeries, and more doctors’ appointments than the average person. Compared to most other people with sickle cell, however, my hospital visits and number of transfusions are pretty low. I didn't have to miss out on school and other life events as much. Unless I tell you, you won't know that this is something that I go through.</p>
<p>When I was younger, I really hated getting hospitalized. It always made me feel weak, and vulnerable. But at the same time, it was also what showed me how much my parents, siblings, and friends cared about me. And those moments of care usually helped me a lot during the times when I was depressed. In its own way, it could fend off the “nobody cares about me” thoughts.</p>
<p>Sickle cell is not who I am, it's just something that happens to me. Even before I really started to know God, a pain crisis wasn't really something that I feared daily. I just worked to do what I need to do to keep it low; drink water, stay warm, rest often, take my meds etc. But I’m not super meticulous about the whole process. Some days I don’t take my medication, sometimes I push myself a little bit when doing rigorous activities, and sometimes I forget my jacket on a cool day.</p>
<p>I used to ask God often, why me? Why did I have to have this condition? Why do I have to deal with this? As I’ve gotten to know God, there are some verses that I take comfort in whenever these thoughts start to creep in; <a>John 9:1-3</a> and <a>2 Corinthians 12: 8-10</a>. Throughout my journey with Christ, I've grown even less fearful of getting a pain crisis than I used to be. I'm still learning what the word has to say about healing, and sickness, but I do know that the Spirit of Christ is what gives me life (<a>Romans 8:10-11</a>), not my blood.</p>
<p>When I accepted Christ, I was born again, I became a new creature (<a>2 Corinthians 5:17</a>). I may have been born into this world with sickle cell, but I was reborn in the spirit realm perfectly whole, lacking in nothing. I don't fear getting a pain crisis, I don't fear getting sick. Sure, I may still get symptoms, but it's nothing I can't overcome with God. Besides, to live is Christ and to die is gain (<a>Philippians 1:21</a>).</p>
<p>Infirmities are hard to deal with and everyone deals with them differently, but in all things, I know that God will bring me through it. Sickness doesn't rule me, Christ does, because greater is He that is in me, than he that is in the world (<a>1 John 4:4</a>).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-anna-shvets-3786126-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prayer for decernment and protection]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/prayer-for-decernment-and-protection</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/prayer-for-decernment-and-protection</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[We are in tough times, but we have a tough God! If you're feeling weak, go to God in prayer, he will renew and restore your spirit.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lord,</p>
<p>In this time of uncertainty I pray for discernment. May your truth be revealed to me. May your truth be revealed to your sheep, and to all who seek the truth. I praise you God because even during these difficult times you are in control! You are opening blind eyes, and you are softening hardened hearts.</p>
<p>Your word declares that no weapon formed against me shall prosper! The Spirit of the living God dwells in me, of whom shall I be afraid? Lord, I dwell in your secret place, and I find rest in your shadow! I cast my worries unto you, my rock, and my foundation, the source of my strength! You've promised that your word will never return to you void oh God! I thank you for your protection.</p>
<p>Holy spirit, I thank you for your guidance, I thank you for your comfort, and I thank you for leading me in paths of righteousness! I thank you for with you my cup overflows with blessings, and with grace. Your mercy is never-ending, they are new every morning!</p>
<p>I give you all the honor, all the glory, and all the praise. In Jesus' Name, Amen!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-binti-malu-2927676-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jesus’ Commandments]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/jesus’-commandments</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/jesus’-commandments</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Many people think that Jesus' commands are the 10 commandments. Lets take a deeper look at what the Bible says.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Those who follow the commands of Jesus have access to many promises. Many people think that these commands are the 10 commandments. While they aren’t completely off the mark, they have still missed the mark. Jesus commanded us to love our neighbor, stating that it’s equally as important as worshiping only God (<a>Mark 12:29-31</a>, <a>Matthew 22:37-40</a>).</p>
<p>In <a>John 15 verse 12</a> Jesus says, “This is my commandment: Love each other in the same way I have loved you”. Then not much later he says again in verse 17 “This is my command: Love each other”. He tells us this so that we would know what he means when he tells us in <a>verse 10</a> “When you obey my commandments, you remain in my love…”.</p>
<p>You may be wondering, what about the 10 commandments? God gave the law to Moses for the Israelis to follow in the Old Testament. It was given as a standard for righteousness and also to show people just how hard it is to be sinless by their own effort. It exemplifies why we need a savior. Jesus overcame the law when he died on the cross (<a>Romans 10:3-4</a>). Paul also reiterates <a>Matthew 22:40</a> in <a>Galatians 5 verse 14</a> saying “For the whole law can be summed up in this one command: “Love your neighbor as yourself”.</p>
<p>John points out in <a>1 John 2:7</a> that this command is not new! It may seem new, but it really isn't. It is just been rephrased. <a>Verse 9 of 1 John 2</a> also states that if you claim to love God and hate your neighborhood, then you are living in darkness. He says this after telling us in <a>verse 5</a> of the previous chapter, that God is light, and there is no darkness in him at all! If you're living in darkness, then God has no part in you! So always strive to live in the light! Remember, “Three things will last forever—faith, hope, and love—and the greatest of these is love” (<a>1 Corinthians 13</a>).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-cqfavocat-613508-1024x683.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Benefits of Praying in Tongues]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/benefits-of-praying-in-tongues</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/benefits-of-praying-in-tongues</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Before Jesus ascended into heaven, he instructed the apostles to wait on the Holy Spirit. When the Holy Spirit arrived, the first gift given was the ability to speak in tongues Acts 2:4. Which means that they were able to speak in a language that was foreign to them. Here I will tell you of 2 benefits of praying in tongues.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>These miraculous signs will accompany those who believe: They will cast out demons in my name, and they will speak in new languages. They will be able to handle snakes with safety, and if they drink anything poisonous, it won’t hurt them. They will be able to place their hands on the sick, and they will be healed.”</p>
<cite>Mark 16:17-18 NLT</cite></blockquote>
<p>Before Jesus ascended into heaven, he instructed the apostles to wait on the Holy Spirit. When the Holy Spirit arrived, the first gift given was the ability to speak in tongues (<a>Acts 2:4</a>). Which means that they were able to speak in a language that was foreign to them. This was also a sign to the unbelievers there of what the Holy Spirit was capable of (<a>Acts 2:</a>, <a>1 Cor 14:22</a>).</p>
<p>Praying in tongues is slightly different from speaking in tongues. However, praying is still a form of speaking. Most of the time when we speak, we are trying to communicate something to another individual. But when we pray, we are communicating with God. Below are 2 benefits that Paul gives for praying in tongues.</p>
<h3>1) You’re speaking directly to God</h3>
<p>In <a>1 Corinthians 14:2</a> Paul states that “For if you have the ability to speak in tongues, you will be talking only to God”. This means that demons or Satan can’t understand you. You’re getting personal with God, therefore growing your relationship with him. We can be confident in what we say, even if we don’t understand, because as Paul continues to say in the same verse “You will be speaking by the power of the Spirit…”. If the Holy Spirit is the one given you the utterance, then you know you are saying powerful and important things to God.</p>
<p>Then in <a>verses 14-15</a>. Paul encourages us by saying that even if we don’t understand, we should still pray in tongues; and on top of that pray in our understanding. So, when praying, it’s okay to go back and forth between praying with the spirit and praying with your mind or words you understand. This is helpful because when you run out of things to say, you can let the spirit continue for you!</p>
<h3>2) You’re strengthening yourself</h3>
<p>In <a>1 Corinthians 14:4</a> Paul lets us know “A person who speaks in tongues is strengthened personally…”. So, the more you do it, the more you are strengthened. This would be why Paul boasts in v.18 “I thank God that I speak in tongues more than any of you”. The only way to be able to have such a boast is to be praying in tongues often in your private time. This in turn also helps to build your relationship and understanding of God.</p>
<p>When praying in the spirit, you know that your prayer time can last for as long as you want it to. You won’t have to feel stuck about what to say next because the Holy Spirit has you covered. Also, if at any time you want to know what you are saying, Paul also encourages us to ask for the gift of interpretation in <a>v.13.</a></p>
<h3>Can everyone pray in tongues?</h3>
<p>Everyone may not have the gift of speaking in tongues, that is another human language, but everyone has their own spirit given language that only God can understand. While it's not always possible to have someone be able to interpret your tongues to edify everyone around you, praying in tongues edifies you. This means that everyone has the ability to pray in tongues. All that is required is faith, willingness, and prayer time. Ask God for the gift, and don’t be afraid to receive it once you get it. It will seem strange at first, but the more you do it, the more you will be strengthened. Remember the Holy Spirit won't force anything on you, it's up to you to accept or reject any gift given to you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>But you, dear friends, must build each other up in your most holy faith,<b> pray in the power of the Holy Spirit</b>, and await the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ, who will bring you eternal life. In this way, you will keep yourselves safe in God’s love</p>
<cite>Jude 1:20-2</cite></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-luis-quintero-2774546-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What is my new nature?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-is-my-new-nature</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/what-is-my-new-nature</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I’ve been thinking lately a lot about what it means to be born again. What does it mean to become a new creature while I am still on this earth?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>For we died and were buried with Christ by baptism. And just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glorious power of the Father, now we also may live new lives.</p>
<cite>Romans 6:4 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>I’ve been thinking lately a lot about what it means to be born again. What does it mean to become a new creature while I am still on this earth? it’s hard to really see our new nature in the moment. It’s only when we look back at where we were, that we really see how far Jesus has taken us. After some study, here are 3 points on what it means to be a new creature (<a>2 Corinthians 5:</a>).</p>
<h5>Made Righteous</h5>
<p>As a new creature, we are made right with God through Christ (<a>2 Corinthians 5:21</a>). This Is an important first step because now it’s easier to go to God with our worries. We don’t have to pray feeling ashamed of things we’ve done before we knew Him. Our ability to form a relationship with God is jump-started because we are now alive to God (<a>Romans 6:11</a>).</p>
<h5>Become Joyful</h5>
<p>We are given joy overflowing and peace that surpasses understanding (<a>Philippians 4:7</a>, <a> John 15:11</a>). Jesus left us with his Joy and with it comes peace and rest. This is why in <a>Philippians 4:4</a> Paul urges us to rejoice in the Lord always. Even when things get hard, we know that we can still have Joy in understanding where we’re going.</p>
<h5>Christ is in us</h5>
<p>As a new creature, we have the nature of Christ. Thanks to the Holy Spirit, we not only are able to remain in Christ, but our spirit is one with Christ’s (<a>Colossians 1:27</a>). The more we live using our new nature, the deeper our relationship with the Holy Spirit can become and the more like Christ we become (<a>Colossians 3:10</a>.</p>
<p>For these to manifest in your life, you must know you have it and use it. That’s why Paul says we need to renew our minds (<a>Romans 12:2</a>). Renewing our minds, helps us to know God’s will for us in his kingdom. So, if you are born again, know that these are just a few things that are now available to you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Instead, let the Spirit renew your thoughts and attitudes. Put on your new nature, created to be like God—truly righteous and holy.</p>
<cite>Ephesians 4:23-24 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-andrea-piacquadio-3756168-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Put on the Full Armor of God]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/put-on-the-full-armor-of-god</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/put-on-the-full-armor-of-god</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[In Ephesians 6 starting from verse 10, Paul warns everyone to be strong in the Lord and to put on his full armor. Let's take a closer look at the armor and what exactly it's protecting.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Therefore, put on every piece of God’s armor so you will be able to resist the enemy in the time of evil. Then after the battle you will still be standing firm. Stand your ground, putting on the belt of truth and the body armor of God’s righteousness. <sup>15</sup> For shoes, put on the peace that comes from the Good News so that you will be fully prepared. In addition to all of these, hold up the shield of faith to stop the fiery arrows of the devil. Put on salvation as your helmet, and take the sword of the Spirit, which is the word of God. Pray in the Spirit at all times and on every occasion. Stay alert and be persistent in your prayers for all believers everywhere.</p>
<cite>Ephesians 6:13-18 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>In <a>Ephesians 6</a> starting from verse 10, Paul warns everyone to be strong in the Lord and to put on his full armor. Since we do not battle against the physical things of this world, but the things of the spiritual, or unseen, world (<a>Ephesians 6:12</a>). Let’s take a closer look at the armor and what exactly it’s protecting.</p>
<p>Starting from verse 14, the first thing we are advised to put on is the belt of truth. It’s important that we know the truth of what’s really happening around us. We must understand our surroundings and know the truth of the battlefield.</p>
<p>Next is the body armor of righteousness. We need to make sure our body parts are protected from any immediate physical attacks. Therefore, we must cover ourselves in the righteousness that is awarded to us when we believe in Christ. We take that and strengthen it. As we continue in righteousness, we change the armor from being made of bronze to being made of diamond and being impenetrable by any evil spirit’s attack on our bodies.</p>
<p>Then in verse 15 it’s the shoes, which is the peace that comes from the Gospel. With this piece, we know that we can step anywhere on the battlefield and be fine. It doesn’t matter whether we are fighting in the trenches, or in minefields, our shoes will protect and guide us. We are fully prepared.</p>
<p>In addition to the shoes, we hold up the shield of faith (verse 16). This shield stops the fiery arrows of the devil. This way, any long-distance attacks will not penetrate because our faith is the assurance that our victory is set. No matter what may come our way, as we build our faith, we shield ourselves from his devices. With our faith, we are not ignorant of Satan’s devices.</p>
<p>Following suit in verse 17, we are to put on salvation as our helmet. This way, no matter what thoughts are sent to us, we know our salvation is assured. We protect our salvation by the renewing of our mind. By turning our heads towards Christ and affirming our salvation. Then, it’s the sword of the spirit, the word of God, which with everything else, allows us to fight! On this battlefield, we are on the offense when we use the word of God. Therefore, the word of God must stay on our lips. We must always choose to speak life.</p>
<p>With all this armor, we must never, ever forget our strongest weapon, prayer (Verse 18)! We have the armor to defend ourselves and keep us standing. And the sword to keep the enemy at bay, but with prayer, we make the power of God available to take down all enemies. Let us never get weary of prayer brethren, but in all things, let's make our petitions known to God, so that we may be able to win all our battles.</p>
<p>Be sure to daily put on your armor so that you can stand strong in all your battles. Also, never cease to pray, for all things, in all things, and through all things. Both are important as we go through our daily battles. Always remember, even if you lose a battle, the war is already won. Jesus conquered all, he is Lord of lords and King of kings. He is the great I AM, the alpha and the omega, the beginning and the end. Glory!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-161936-1024x680.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A lesson from Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego.]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/a-lesson-from-shadrach-meshach-and-abednego</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/a-lesson-from-shadrach-meshach-and-abednego</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Who is the God that you serve? Is He your genie that you call on only when you need something? Or is He the all-powerful, almighty, creator of all the universe?]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote >
<p>Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego replied, “O Nebuchadnezzar, we do not need to defend ourselves before you. If we are thrown into the blazing furnace, the God whom we serve is able to save us. He will rescue us from your power, Your Majesty. But even if he doesn’t, we want to make it clear to you, Your Majesty, that we will never serve your gods or worship the gold statue you have set up.”</p>
<cite>Daniel 3:16—18</cite></blockquote>
<p>Who is the God that you serve? Is He your genie that you call on only when you need something? Or is He the all-powerful, almighty, creator of all the universe? Sometimes we think that being blessed or favored only happens when we get exactly what we want, or only when things that we see as good happen to us.</p>
<p>Whether we are going through the valleys, or standing on the mountains, God is God. He loves us, He’s with us, and He’s in control. Just because our current conditions aren’t exceptional doesn’t mean that God doesn’t care. It doesn’t mean that He’s left us, or that He doesn’t know what’s going on. God always know what’s going on, and He’s always in control.</p>
<p>Like Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego said in Daniel 3:18 "even if he doesn’t”. Even if God doesn’t rescue me from the fiery furnace, I will still worship him. Even when the going gets tough, I will still praise God. I don’t think a lot of people can say that.</p>
<p>I know that most times I tend to doubt God when I’ve prayed and prayed, and my situation doesn’t change, or I doubt my faith and my salvation. But that shouldn’t be the case, because I should have assurance that no matter what happens, God is still sovereign, I’m still covered, and the outcome is still for my good. I might be going through hardship now, but eternity will be nothing compared to this short time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-harry-cunningham-harrydigital-3619860-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Psalm 42]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/psalm-42</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/psalm-42</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[When I get sad or discouraged, I like to read Psalm 42. I find it to be a great example of scripture that is easy to resonate with. It also reminds me to continue to look to God.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
When I get sad or discouraged, I like to read <a>Psalm 42</a>. I find it to be a great example of scripture that is easy to resonate with. It also reminds me to continue to look to God.
</p>
<p>
From the very first verse, I already feel as if I’m the one speaking: “As the deer longs for streams of water, so I long for you, O God”. In these moments, I always long to be in the presence of God, to be overwhelmed by His warm light. I always like to imagine receiving a consoling hug from Jesus. Which goes into verse 2, “I thirst for God, the living God. When can I go and stand before him?”
</p>
<p>
Then verse 4 also really hits home, because usually when I’m sad or discouraged, I think back on when last I enjoyed myself. I think back on the last time I didn’t feel this way and try to figure out what changed. At which point I ask myself verse 5: “why am I discouraged? Why is my heart so sad? I will put my hope in God! I will praise him again, my Savior and my God!"
</p>
<p>
Then sometimes, I may go through verse 9 where I question everything, including God. I’m constantly asking why, why, why? But then, I go back to verse 8: “but each day, the Lord pours his unfailing love upon me, and through each night I sing his songs, praying to God who gives me life”. I am reminded that I should keep praying, and seeking God, because he knows my heart. I’ve learned to play worship music during these times, instead of songs that help me to wallow in my sorrows. It’s not all about me and when I remember this, I can focus on bigger things.
</p>
<p>
Going through the valleys sometimes can be hard, but I like to hold on to Psalm 42 as a reminder that God is with me through it all. It’s okay to be sad and feel down, but it’s not okay to forget God because of it. God gave us emotions, and we are free to experience them. However, we need to be careful about how we express them. We should be able to honor God in and through all things.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-valeria-ushakova-3094210-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3 things to Keep in Mind as you grow in your faith]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/3-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-you-grow-in-your-faith</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/3-things-to-keep-in-mind-as-you-grow-in-your-faith</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Being a Christian isn't always easy, but we've got to remember to stay bold and preach the good news to the world. Romans 1:16 -> For I am not ashamed of the gospel because it is the power of God that brings salvation to everyone who believes: first to the Jew, then to the Gentile.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>1. Have a fear of God not man</h3>
<p>Sometimes as Christian's if we're not careful, we can easily get into the habit of always wanting to be tolerable to non-believers. While we should do all things in love, we shouldn't have to compromise who we are and what we believe in. Just because someone is accusing you of being boring, uptight, judgmental, etc. doesn't change the truth of what God has called you: a chosen people, a royal priesthood, and a holy nation (<a>1 Peter 2:9</a>). While in the face of persecution it can be easy to want to take the path of least resistance, but that's not the mindset we should have. We should be bold and follow the examples of Joshua and Caleb (<a>Numbers 14:6-9</a>), Daniel and his buddies (<a>Daniel 3:17-18</a>, <a>6:13</a>), Peter (<a>Acts 5:28-29</a>) and countless others in the Bible. We are called to do God's will, not man's will. So be prepared for persecution.</p>
<h3>2. It's all about Jesus and his kingdom</h3>
<p>We shouldn't be too prideful, or selfish but should humble ourselves in all things. When boasting, boast in God who provides us with all things needed to live a godly life in Christ (<a>2 Peter 1:3</a>). Our salvation was a gift, and not earned (<a>Ephesians 2:8-10</a>). Everything we do as Christians is to further the kingdom of God. As Matthew 6:33 states, Seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added onto you. This isn't to say that we can't take care of ourselves, or want things like cars, houses, marriage, money, etc. All that is fine, as long as we're not consumed by all these things to the point where God becomes our genie. Our purpose is to serve God, not for God to serve us. And the beautiful thing about God is that if we serve Him, he will take care of us.</p>
<h3>3. It's the why that matters not the what</h3>
<p>Jesus cares more for the state of our heart than the actions that we do. If we are following his commandments for self-righteous reasons and not out of love for him, then it doesn't mean much (<a>1 Samuel 16:7</a>). Empty religious actions pale in comparison to a heart seeking after God (<a >Matthew 9:13</a>). In everything that we do, we should seek God whole heartily and when we do, we will find him for he draws near to those who seek him (<a>Psalm 34:17-18</a>, <a>Matthew 7:7-8</a>). Keep your prayer life active, and cultivate a relationship with Him. Once you have that relationship, all the do's and don'ts won't seem like such a burden (<a class="tooltips">Matthew 11:28-29</a>).</p>
<p>Work at your faith, and you will be amazed at the things God will reveal to you about who He is.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-magda-ehlers-1329291-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I view Submission]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-i-view-submission</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-i-view-submission</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[From my experience, when people think of being submissive they always think of giving up all control to someone. And by giving up all control they have thereby lost their own freedom. Just because you're submissive, doesn't mean you lose your freedom, depending on the circumstances of which you have to submit.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>You call me ‘Teacher’ and ‘Lord,’ and you are right, because that’s what I am. And since I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you ought to wash each other’s feet. I have given you an example to follow. Do as I have done to you.</p>
<cite>John 13:13-15 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>From my experience, when people think of being submissive they always think of giving up all control to someone. And by giving up all control they have thereby lost their own freedom. Just because you're submissive, doesn't mean you lose your freedom, depending on the circumstances of which you have to submit.</p>
<p>When it comes to being submissive in a marriage, it shouldn't mean losing all freedom. This isn't an opportunity for the husband to say: "I'm the head, so you must do everything I say!" and be tyrannical. <a>Ephesians 5:25-28</a> says: "For husbands, this means love your wives, just as Christ loved the church. He gave up his life for her to make her holy and clean, washed by the cleansing of God’s word. He did this to present her to himself as a glorious church without a spot or wrinkle or any other blemish. Instead, she will be holy and without fault. In the same way, husbands ought to love their wives as they love their own bodies. For a man who loves his wife actually shows love for himself".</p>
<p>So a husband should love himself enough to be able to love his wife as Christ loved the church. How did Christ love the church? The answer lies in <a>John 3:16</a>. Jesus was willing to sacrifice himself for the church, thus a husband should also be willing to sacrifice himself for his wife. And just as the church is submissive to Christ because of his sacrifice, the wife also should be submissive to her husband as it states in <a>Ephesians 5:22-24</a>. the wife should also be able to respect and trust that her husband has the family's best interest at heart.</p>
<p>Outside of marriage we are also to submit not just to God but also to worldly authority. Because of this, sometimes we will experience some hardship but we know that God is watching and will reward us for doing what is right even when in an unpleasant situation (<a>1 Peter 2:19-21</a>). It's also important to keep in mind however that we serve God first and foremost. When submitting to worldly authority we are doing it because it pleases God, not because it pleases man. Thus, anything God tells us during the circumstances supersedes any contradictory orders from worldly authorities.</p>
<p>Having said all this, I still find it challenging for me to submit to a certain authority, even when what they tell me to do doesn't negatively impact my faith. Sometimes my pride takes the better of me, After reading <a>1 Peter 2:13-14</a> and <a>Ephesians 5:21</a> I will be trying to do better. Being meek does not mean that I am weak, and I trust that God will provide grace where it is needed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>... So Jesus got them together to settle things down. He said, “You’ve observed how godless rulers throw their weight around, how quickly a little power goes to their heads. It’s not going to be that way with you. Whoever wants to be great must become a servant. Whoever wants to be first among you must be your slave. That is what the Son of Man has done: He came to serve, not be served—and then to give away his life in exchange for the many who are held hostage.”</p>
<cite>Matthew 20:24-28 MSG</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-262399-626x1024.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How this whole pandemic thing is making me feel.]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-this-whole-pandemic-thing-is-making-me-feel</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-this-whole-pandemic-thing-is-making-me-feel</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The way the world is right now is very saddening. It seems no matter where you turn there is propaganda.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The way the world is right now is very saddening. It seems no matter where you turn there is propaganda. Whether is the fear agenda propaganda, or the plan-demic agenda propaganda.</p>
<p>It's really sad to see that so many people are full of fear of an enemy they can't see. I understand their fear because all we know about it is what the news wants us to know. If my hope wasn't in Christ, I would definitely be more fearful. We've been forced into house arrest with an ethos and pathos reasoning made to look like a logos reasoning. If you keep up with the news all you see is death counts, infection rates, overcrowded hospitals, shortages in stores, lack in leadership, biased research, and the list goes on and on (It's good to take a break from the news every once in a while).</p>
<p>All this just ends up spreading discord; fear mixed with confusion and anger at someone or something. There are a lot of things that don't add up or make sense. Maybe I'm focusing too much on the physical and not enough on the spiritual. At a time like this I just pray that the truth would make itself clear and known to everyone.</p>
<h6>Father God,</h6>
<p>There's so much happening in the world right now and I thank you because you are in control. I thank you because you listen to our prayers. Lord, I ask that all your people have inner peace and that you would draw near to all who seek you. I thank you because we are never truly alone for you are always with us. You are our provider in all circumstances, you are our Shepard. I thank you because everything is happening within its appointed time and not earlier.</p>
<p>Thank you Lord for we have assurance of our salvation through you. We have truth for you are truth, and we have peace in the Gospel. You have given us righteousness and the holy spirit. All this we have through our faith which shields up from the fiery arrows of Satan. Thank you Lord for you have provided us with our whole armor; all we have to do is wear it and fight the good fight.</p>
<p>Thank you Lord for we have hope during these times. Even if things may seem bleak, we know, oh God, that you are a restorer, you are a healer, you are a provider, you are love, and you hold the whole world in the palm of your hands. Especially during these times Lord, I will not lean on my own understanding, but trust in you and let you direct my path.</p>
<p>Thank you Lord for during these times you are softening the hearts of people. The harvest is plentiful during these times oh Lord and the workers are being imparted with boldness, patience, and loving-kindness. We thank you for we are able to preach your word to those who need to hear it. Thank you oh Lord because as your children, we are not afraid of the Gospel; for it is the power of God that brings salvation to everyone who believes. Thank you Lord for even as we go through persecution, we know that you overcame first, so we also can overcome.</p>
<p>All this I pray in Jesus's name, Amen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Why am I discouraged? Why is my heart so sad? I will put my hope in God! I will praise him again— my Savior and my God!</p>
<cite>Psalms 42:11 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-andrea-piacquadio-3762939-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Honor God with your body]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/honor-god-with-your-body</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/honor-god-with-your-body</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Following God is never in vain. The things the world glorify is never worth missing out on the promise of spending eternity with the one who created us and loves us endlessly. We are worth far more than we sometimes think. This post is another testimony.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>you were bought with a high price. So you must honor God with your body.</p>
<cite>1 Corinthians 6:20</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>Watching the Relationship Goals series by Pastor Mike Todd of Transformation Church on YouTube, made me realize that there was something that I wasn't yet willing to give up for God. Because it was something I thought I was helpless agaisnt. Especially because I got comfortable with it before getting to know Christ.</p>
<p>To paint the picture, I had a season right after starting college where sex was my coping mechanism. Cutting was no longer something I could hide since my counselor would actively look for any signs of self-harm of that nature and notify my family. Sex was an easier alternative because it was a more socially acceptable way of harming myself; I didn't really do it because I enjoyed the act.</p>
<p>When I got saved, however, I realized that I could no longer use sex as a coping mechanism. But because I was so used to it, I was still bound by it. While I was given the ability to overcome it, I still made excuses for it while in a relationship. I didn't fight or say no when my partner would ask for sex. While I would bring up abstinence every once in a while, I didn't make it clear that it was something I wanted to pursue. In the back of my mind, I wasn't fully willing to let go of it.</p>
<p>Though Sex wasn't something I really enjoyed that much, when the urge came, it was something I couldn't fight. It had a stronghold over me, where I couldn't think straight until the act was done. Then after doing it, I would just hate and feel very ashamed of myself. I didn't realize it at the time but I was a slave to sex, masturbation, and porn.</p>
<p>Pastor Todd's series really helped to open my eyes on how much I had allowed sex to rule over my life. Especially part 7 of his message; Does Sex own you? After watching that, I realized that yes, it does own me. But thank God that now I am willing to allow God to work with and through me so that I can be set free from this bondage. The difference between now and before is that even though I knew better, I wasn't willing to do better. I hadn't truly repented. <a>2 Corinthians 7:10</a> says: "For the kind of sorrow God wants us to experience leads us away from sin and results in salvation. There’s no regret for that kind of sorrow. But worldly sorrow, which lacks repentance, results in spiritual death"</p>
<p>True repentance leads to change, it's not just feeling bad about our actions. Though it may seem hard to do sometimes, it's always worth the trouble, especially if you understand that the things of this world do not compare to the things of heaven. So if you have to cast out any demon(s) you got comfortable with, cast it out. It can't possibly offer you anything that would bring you life.</p>
<p>Thinking about abstaining until marriage? Here is a video by Queen Dani on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ShvT6q6XL50" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Untold Truths About Waiting Until Marriage To Have Sex</strong></a>. It's a great watch and is sure to leave you with a different perspective.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>..."Or did you think that because he's such a nice God, he'd let you off the hook? Better think this one through from the beginning. God is kind, but he's not soft. In kindness he takes us firmly by the hand and leads us into a radical life-change."</p>
<cite>Romans 2:4 (MSG)</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/girl-and-penguin-figurine-3274626.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Turning Back - My Journey to Christ]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/no-turning-back-my-journey-to-christ</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/no-turning-back-my-journey-to-christ</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I made up my mind to get to know Christ my sophomore year of College. Find out why.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made up my mind to get to know Christ my sophomore year of College. Why? Well, I was at a point where I just didn't have anything meaningful to hang on to in this world. I remember thinking; "the only way for my life to have meaning, is for me to find something to define it. I might as well let it be God, at least then I won't have to rely on myself".</p>
<p>At the time I really hated and didn't trust myself, so finding meaning through myself just seemed like an endless cycle of unknowns. I was already confused enough and tired of trying one thing just for it fail.  Defining my purpose just to not be motivated enough to pursue it got really tedious, especially since it all seemed meaningless anyway. I didn't want anything that life had to offer, I just wanted death; which I had just failed at acquiring two years prior and wasn't about to try and fail again. I was fed up with failing, especially since I wasn't working towards something that meant anything to me.</p>
<p>Then, one day after relapsing, I sat there arm bleeding and made up my mind that once back on campus, I would look for a church. It wasn't super easy to do, but I also was tired of feeling helpless, useless and empty. In addition to finding a church, I made it my goal to read the Bible through from Genesis to Revelations. The verses I hung on to when I first started reading, where the ones that validated my feelings, my favorite one at the time being  <a>Ecclesiastes 4:2-3</a>. There were also other verses that helped me feel a little less empty, like  <a>Matthew 6:25-34</a>. To this day, I would say <a>Matthew 6:25-34</a> is still one of my favorite passages.</p>
<p>One thing also that I'm really grateful for was that I was able to make new friends who showed me that living a Christ filled life is not all about religious regulations. I can totally be myself, because that's who God made me to be. The challenge being that I had to redefine myself since I had let go of so much of myself. Building my life back hasn't been a piece of cake, but as time has passed, it's gone from bad to better to pretty great.</p>
<p>While I don't get depressed anymore like I used to, I am definitely ready for Christ's return so I can leave this earth. I've been a bit better at managing my emotions, but sometimes they get the better of me, whether I'm feeling too much or not enough. Allowing myself to feel is probably one of the tougher challenges.</p>
<p>I definitely can't go back, but I am also working on not being carnally minded after every thing Christ has done for me. If he died for me, then I can live for him.</p>
<p> I still have a long ways to go, but He's definitely walking me through every step of the way. He's not finished with me yet!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>
“I tell you, her sins—and they are many—have been forgiven, so she has shown me much love. But a person who is forgiven little shows only little love.”
</p>
<cite>Luke 7:47 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-alex-tim-1183986-1024x680.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why we need salvation]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-we-need-salvation</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/why-we-need-salvation</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[For there to be good news, there would need to be an alternate bad situation. Lets not take for granted what we have been given. Here is why we need salvation.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>“Today I have given you the choice between life and death, between blessings and curses. Now I call on heaven and earth to witness the choice you make. Oh, that you would choose life, so that you and your descendants might live!</p>
<cite>Deuteronomy 30:19 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<h5>1. We are all born into death</h5>
<p>
<a>Romans 5:12-14</a> says: "When Adam sinned, sin entered the world. Adam’s sin brought death, so death spread to everyone, for everyone sinned.Yes, people sinned even before the law was given. But it was not counted as sin because there was not yet any law to break. Still, everyone died—from the time of Adam to the time of Moses—even those who did not disobey an explicit commandment of God, as Adam did...".</p>
<p>The death Paul is referring to here isn't our physical death, but our spiritual death. When you are born into this world, you are already spiritually dead. What does it mean to be spiritually dead? It means to be separated or cut off from God.</p>
<p>Once born, it's up to us to choose life. The only way to receive life is through Jesus. He told us he is the way, the truth, and the life, and no one gets to the Father except through him (<a>John 14:6</a>).</p>
<h5>2. God is Just</h5>
<p><a>2 Peter 2:4-7</a> shows an example of what happens to the ungodly: "For God did not spare even the angels who sinned. He threw them into hell,in gloomy pits of darkness,where they are being held until the day of judgment.And God did not spare the ancient world—except for Noah and the seven others in his family. Noah warned the world of God’s righteous judgment. So God protected Noah when he destroyed the world of ungodly people with a vast flood.Later, God condemned the cities of Sodom and Gomorrah and turned them into heaps of ashes. He made them an example of what will happen to ungodly people.But God also rescued Lot out of Sodom because he was a righteous man who was sick of the shameful immorality of the wicked people around him.</p>
<p>This Earth is not our final destination. There will be wickedness up until Satan is finally thrown into the lake of fire along with all his followers. God will judge the world again and the only way to escape being part of the judgment is to accept Jesus. Jesus tells us in <a>John 12:47-48</a> "I will not judge those who hear me but don’t obey me, for I have come to save the world and not to judge it. But all who reject me and my message will be judged on the day of judgment by the truth I have spoken".</p>
<h5>3. The 2nd death won't be pleasant</h5>
<p>"Then the devil, who had deceived them, was thrown into the fiery lake of burning sulfur, joining the beast and the false prophet. There they will be tormented day and night forever and ever" <a>Revelations 20:10</a>.</p>
<p>"And I saw a great white throne and the one sitting on it. The earth and sky fled from his presence, but they found no place to hide. I saw the dead, both great and small, standing before God’s throne. And the books were opened, including the Book of Life. And the dead were judged according to what they had done, as recorded in the books.The sea gave up its dead, and death and the grave gave up their dead. And all were judged according to their deeds.Then death and the grave were thrown into the lake of fire. This lake of fire is the second death.And anyone whose name was not found recorded in the Book of Life was thrown into the lake of fire" <a>Revelations 20:11-15</a>.</p>
<p>"But cowards, unbelievers, the corrupt, murderers, the immoral, those who practice witchcraft, idol worshipers, and all liars—their fate is in the fiery lake of burning sulfur. This is the second death" <a>Revelations 21:8</a>.</p>
<p>In every parable you hear Jesus talking about people being tossed into the lake of fire, there is always weeping and gnashing of teeth. This shows just how awful hell will be. I'm sure that just as the pleasures of heaven are too great for us to imagine, the torture of hell is just as great. But that's why Jesus died, so that we may have eternal life instead of eternal death (<a>John 3:16</a>).</p>
<p>“He who has an ear, let him hear what the Spirit says to the churches. He who overcomes shall not be hurt by the second death” <a>Revelations 2:11 NKJV</a>.</p>
<p>So make your choice, would you rather have eternal life or eternal death?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>That’s the whole story. Here now is my final conclusion: Fear God and obey his commands, for this is everyone’s duty.God will judge us for everything we do, including every secret thing, whether good or bad.</p>
<cite>Ecclesiastes 12:13-14 NLT</cite></blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/jesus-3643027_1280-1024x642.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy Easter 2020!]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/happy-easter-2020</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/happy-easter-2020</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Happy Easter 2020!  It's not because he died, but because he rose again that we have good news to share!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>
Then the angel spoke to the women. “Don’t be afraid!” he said. “I know you are looking for Jesus, who was crucified. He isn’t here! He is risen from the dead, just as he said would happen. Come, see where his body was lying. And now, go quickly and tell his disciples that he has risen from the dead, and he is going ahead of you to Galilee. You will see him there. Remember what I have told you.”
</p>
<cite>Matthew 28:5-7</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
Happy Easter! The Good news isn't that Jesus died, but that he rose again! Today we celebrate his victory over death and the grave! He reigns victorious!! He is sitting at God's right hand! All power and strength and glory belong to Him! Thanks to his resurrection, we have been given eternal life!
</p>
<p>
The sacrificial lamb, the son of God, he is worthy of all praise, all honor, and all praise!!!
</p>
<p>
GLOOOORRRRYYYYYY!!!!!!
</p>
<blockquote>
Jesus came and told his disciples, “I have been given all authority in heaven and on earth. Therefore, go and make disciples of all the nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit. Teach these new disciples to obey all the commands I have given you. And be sure of this: I am with you always, even to the end of the age.”
<cite>Matthew 28:18-20 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/rocks-1239727_1280-1024x576.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A conversation about relationships]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/a-conversation-about-relationships</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/a-conversation-about-relationships</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Recently I started thinking about relationships and why we put so much weight on them. I needed someone to talk to about it, so I did what any sibling would do and I reached out to my little sister.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Recently I started thinking about relationships and why we put so much weight on them. I needed someone to talk to about it, so I did what any sibling would do and I reached out to my little sister. Below is a portion of our back and forth that really got me thinking, and also brought some assurance.
</p>
<hr />
<p>
<b>Me:</b> I've just been thinking about relationships and how exhausting they are and the reasons behind why people date/break up/get married.
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> Like it all seems so superficial after everything.
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> It's like Ultimately we get into a relationship to satisfy our desire to be loved by another individual, as well as our longing to be able to pour ourselves into someone and be accepted.
</p>
<p>
<b>Her:</b> Yeah, the desire comes from God because we ultimately seek to be loved by Him. Relationships/marriage is just so that other person can show you characteristics of God from a different perspective
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> Yeah, so basically, with God we should be fulfilled already. So why do we continue to look towards another for things Christ has already given us?
</p>
<p>
<b>Her:</b> Because sin
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> Lol, I guess. But we should be freed from the power of sin, and it should no longer dictate our actions
</p>
<p>
<b>Her:</b> We are freed from sin, but that doesn't mean we won't have desires from some things of this earth. Our flesh and spirit are always at war, we just choose who we want to live according to
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> But you are not controlled by your sinful nature. You are controlled by the Spirit if you have the Spirit of God living in you. (And remember that those who do not have the Spirit of Christ living in them do not belong to him at all.)
<a>Romans 8:9 </a>
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> Yeah, but if we've already chosen to let Christ be Lord, why should we still battle with sin?
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> (Sorry, I'm not coming at you or anything, nor am I saying that you're wrong. I'm just challenging our thoughts)
</p>
<p>
<b>Me:</b> The Spirit of God, who raised Jesus from the dead, lives in you. And just as God raised Christ Jesus from the dead, he will give life to your mortal bodies by this same Spirit living within you. Therefore, dear brothers and sisters, you have no obligation to do what your sinful nature urges you to do. For if you live by its dictates, you will die. But if through the power of the Spirit you put to death the deeds of your sinful nature, you will live.
<a>Romans 8:11-13</a>
</p>
<p>
<b>Her:</b> I agree, I think I disagree with the statement that we get into relationships because we desire to be loved by another individual. I think that is true for people who aren't Christians. But for Christians, they should be satisfied with the love they receive from Christ. Christ may put in you the desire to be with someone because He may want you to get married because His plan for you is to glorify Him in your marriage, but not all are called to get married. Ultimately if we seek relationships we should be seeking it because we want to Glorify God with it not because we are lacking
</p>
<hr />
<p>
I was really touched by this conversation. Conversing with others about Christ is such an enriching process. I recommend it for everyone. Find Christians you trust and bounce ideas off each other. Both parties usually end up learning from each other.
</p>
<p>
What are your thoughts on the conversation? Leave a comment below!
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-william-fortunato-6140667-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No matter the situation, God deserves all the praise]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/no-matter-the-situation-god-deserves-all-the-praise</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/no-matter-the-situation-god-deserves-all-the-praise</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Praising God is a way to remind us of who He is. Through every season God deserves all the praise. God doesn't stop being God despite what our situation may be.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
Lord You are good and Your mercies endures forever.
</p>
<p>
You are the almighty, the great I AM
</p>
<p>
You are the alpha and omega, the beginning and the end
</p>
<p>
Who is there like You oh Lord in all the Earth?
</p>
<p>
You conquered the giants and split the seas, You stopped the sun in its tracks and defeated nations.
</p>
<p>
I worship You God of heavens armies.
</p>
<p>
All honor and glory and power and strength onto You for You are worthy.
</p>
<p>
You are the creator of the Heavens and the Earth.
</p>
<p>
You are all-powerful, all-knowing, and a very present help in time of need.
</p>
<p>
There are not enough words to speak of Your glory. A lifetime is not enough to give you praise. You are the holy of holies.
</p>
<p>
You hold the whole Earth in the palm of your hands!
</p>
<p>
Who can be against you oh Lord? Who can defy your decrees?
</p>
<p>
You speak and it becomes so, Your word brings life.
</p>
<p>
I give you all the glory, the honor, and the praise.
</p>
<p>
Thank you, in Jesus's name.
</p>
<p>
Amen
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>'It is good to give thanks to the Lord , to sing praises to the Most High.'</p>
<cite> Psalms 92:1</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-luis-quintero-2014775-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't limit God's forgiveness for you]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/dont-limit-gods-forgiveness-for-you</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/dont-limit-gods-forgiveness-for-you</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The level of which you forgive others is the level you'll be able to accept God's forgiveness.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>For his unfailing love toward those who fear him is as great as the height of the heavens above the earth. He has removed our sins as far from us as the east is from the west. The Lord is like a father to his children, tender and compassionate to those who fear him. For he knows how weak we are; he remembers we are only dust.</p>
<cite>Psalms 103:11-14 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
The level of which you forgive others is the level you'll be able to accept God's forgiveness for yourself because that's the extend of which you perceive forgiveness to go. By limiting how much you forgive someone, you're limiting how much God is able to forgive you. You're limiting your peace of mind, because you think God forgives in the same fashion as you.
</p>
<p>
This is not so, the minute you're born again, you become a child of God and the bible says that as far as the east is from the west, so have the sins of His children been forgiven. He doesn't hold them against you anymore. He won't come back and say, remember that time you did xyz? Those thoughts are not from God, but from satan, the accuser. So when the Lord says He has forgiven you, know that He won't come back and hold it over you, so you shouldn't hold it over yourself either. And since we know this, we should also use this same method of forgiveness when forgiving others. Don't forget, the bible also says in <a>Matthew 6:14-15</a>: “If you forgive those who sin against you, your heavenly Father will forgive you. But if you refuse to forgive others, your Father will not forgive your sins".
</p>
<p>
So when you go to ask God for forgiveness, be sure to also forgive those who have wronged you. Then rest in the truth that once God has forgiven you, you can move from glory to glory. Repent from it, and continue the good fight of endurance. Besides what do you have to lose other than the bitterness and resentment in your heart?
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Then Peter came to him and asked, “Lord, how often should I forgive someone who sins against me? Seven times?” “No, not seven times,” Jesus replied, “but seventy times seven!</p>
<cite>Matthew 18:21-22 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-victor-freitas-847483-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prayer and Thanksgiving]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/prayer-and-thanksgiving</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/prayer-and-thanksgiving</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Don't worry about anything; instead, pray about everything. Tell God what you need, and thank him for all he has done. Then you will experience God's peace, which exceeds anything we can understand.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Don't worry about anything; instead, pray about everything. Tell God what you need, and thank him for all he has done. Then you will experience God's peace, which exceeds anything we can understand. His peace will guard your hearts and minds as you live in Christ Jesus. And now, dear brothers and sisters, one final thing. Fix your thoughts on what is true, and honorable, and right, and pure, and lovely, and admirable. Think about things that are excellent and worthy of praise. Keep putting into practice all you learned and received from me—everything you heard from me and saw me doing. Then the God of peace will be with you.</p>
<cite> Philippians 4:6-9</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
Thanksgiving is also an important part of prayer. And after you've prayed, don't let discouraging thoughts dominate your mind, but instead think on what is true. Think on what God's word says about the situation. Think of who God is, and all he had done. Thank him, and have faith and know that all good and wonderful things come from God (<a>James 1:17</a>).
</p>
<p>
The devil, our adversary, comes to steal, kill, and destroy (<a>John 10:10</a>). But through Jesus we have power over them. We have been given authority and can cast them out (<a>Mark 16:17</a>).
</p>
<p>
And we also know that if we ask the father for anything, through Jesus, he will give to us (<a>John 16:23</a>). And also <a>Mark 11:24</a> says I tell you, you can pray for anything, and if you believe that you've received it, it will be yours.
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/fog-3050078_1280-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to begin using the Bible as a guide for life]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-begin-using-the-bible-as-a-guide-for-life</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/how-to-begin-using-the-bible-as-a-guide-for-life</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As a babe in the faith it can be difficult to know how to use the Bible as a guide. Here are 6 steps to help propel your journey forward in learning to understand how to use your most important tool as a Christian. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>One has to submit to the word for the word to affect them.</p>
<cite>Pastor Chris Oliyakolome</cite>
</blockquote>
<h5>1. Accept that the Bible is truth.</h5>
<p>
In order to really gain anything from the Bible, you have to believe that it is all it says it is. Just like you believe the science books you read in school. Just like you believe the documentaries you watch. Just like you believe non-fiction book you read. In the same way you believe in education systems of the world, you must also believe in the education system of God.
</p>
<h5>2. Let go of preconceived notions, and don't be stubborn for the sake of being stubborn.</h5>
<p>
When reading passages that make you react negatively or that bring doubt, examine why you are reacting to it that way. Does your reaction to it make sense? Are you able to find a biblical explanation that backs up that reaction? Are you hardening your heart to the words because it doesn't quite fit in nicely to what you want to believe or even how you feel? You won't always be able to answer all the questions, but the point here is to take some time to examine your heart. After all the examination, you have the free will to choose what you will do.
</p>
<h5>3. Pray asking the Holy Spirit for revelation as you read.</h5>
<p>
One big thing to understand is that the Bible is not just a book. The point here isn't to read through the book for bragging rights. The Bible is sharper than any two-edged sword (<a>Hebrews 4:12 (NLT)</a>) it exposes our innermost thoughts and desires, it's not only our guide, but also a weapon we use when battling our accuser and his minions (<a>Ephesians 6:10-18 </a>). So, when taking the time to read it, it helps to speak with the Holy Spirit and ask him to soften your heard to be able to accept His word, and to reveal to you the mysteries of God. This also helps to put you in the right mindset as you move forward.
</p>
<h5>4. Meditate on a verse or passage</h5>
<p>
Sometimes instead of reading chapters at a time, the best thing to do is find a passage, or a verse and meditate on it. What I mean by meditate here is to ponder on it, to repeat it to yourself over and over as a mantra. Let your spirit soak in it, let your mind wrap around it, let your heart accept it. Sometimes you can even personalize the verse to be your own. As you meditate on it, you will find that it will stick with you. And when trouble comes you will be able to bring it back to memory and use it. One of my favorite passage in tough times is <a>Matthew 6:25-34</a>.
</p>
<h5>5. Research anything you don't understand</h5>
<p>
Whether it's by reading other passages, asking your small group leader, your pastor, that friend that helped lead you into salvation, or even Google, find the answer to the questions you have or the bits of scripture you don't quite understand. While there are certain things that can't be fully understood, there is still plenty that can. Places like <b>Gotquestions</b>, <b>Biblehub</b>, <b>BibleStudyTools</b>, and <b>Bible Gateway</b> have some very insightful answers for when you're not able to reach out to someone directly. Sometimes, even if you don't have questions, it helps to talk about it with other believers, as this can really help broaden your understanding (<a>Proverbs 27:17</a>).
</p>
<p>
I recommend attending bible studies if you are able, if not start a small one; it can be just you and one other person. I also encourage going to church, as pastors also shed more light into some of the things you've read, and churches usually have small groups that you can join, and many elders and leaders you can turn to. If ever you're in doubt about what you hear from someone, question them about it, and study for yourself as well to make sure it's biblically accurate.
</p>
<h5>6. Put what you now know into practice!</h5>
<p>
All those steps I just listed are meaningless if you don't do anything with what you read (<a>James 1:22-25</a>). As you read, you must also apply it to your life. Grow your faith, expand your understanding, confess the word into your actions, acknowledge that God is who he says he is. It could be as simple as waking up and declaring "today is the day that the Lord has made, I will rejoice and be glad in it" -- <a>Psalm 118:24</a>. Or acknowledging that nature and everything in it was ordained by God. When hard times comes, practice peace, patience, love, joy, self-control. Pray in all things, seek God as much as you can. As you do this, watch how your life will begin to change.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Study to shew thyself approved unto God, a workman that needeth not to be ashamed, rightly dividing the word of truth.</p>
<cite>2 Timothy 2:15 KJV</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
<b>Have any thoughts, concerns, or testimonies? Don't hesitate to drop a comment below.</b>
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/child-945422_1280-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I know who I am]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-know-who-i-am</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-know-who-i-am</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[It wasn't until I started my journey into getting to know myself through Christ that I really started to understand and accept myself. I knew and accepted that God doesn't make mistakes, because He is God.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
I've often gotten called a tomboy; ever since I was little and even now. Often times I used to feel I probably should have been born a boy. I always seemed to get along better with boys. I wasn't a huge fan of wearing dresses and just didn't have an affinity for a lot of feminine activities. I've gotten a few people ask me if I am gay.
</p>
<p>
While at the time I knew I wasn't gay, I wasn't as sure about my gender. I wasn't as sure about who I was. I doubted if I was even really a girl, but I also knew I wasn't a boy. I never really thought too deep about it, I just kind of learned to accept my confusion and keep going.
</p>
<p>
It wasn't until I started my journey into getting to know myself through Christ that I really started to understand and accept myself. I now know and accept that God doesn't make mistakes, because He is God. Therefore I am definitely a girl. I also know that God made me to be who He wanted me to be. Whether I like feminine or masculine things, that doesn't change the truth that I was created a woman and am a woman. But that also doesn't mean that the things I like don't matter. I can still very much like what I like, and be who I am. I am the wonderful and perfect creation of God.
</p>
<p>
Even today many people still tell me I act like a boy. I don't feel offended, I just smile knowing that they don't really understand who I am. It's not up to them to tell me who I am, because God already told me who I am. God doesn't make mistakes, but the father of lies, Satan, definitely wants us to believe otherwise. That's why I'm glad that I can be secure of my gender and personality.
</p>
<p>
What I think a lot of people don't understand is that it's not your actions that make you a specific sex or gender. Your actions are just a result of the personality that God implanted in you and how you use it. Of course, Satan will do everything he can to make sure you lose your way, but you have to also be willing to do everything you can to make sure that God remains your pillar. Read the Bible, discuss the Bible, act on the Bible and you'll find that it works.
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You made all the delicate, inner parts of my body and knit me together in my mother’s womb. Thank you for making me so wonderfully complex! Your workmanship is marvelous—how well I know it. You watched me as I was being formed in utter seclusion, as I was woven together in the dark of the womb. You saw me before I was born. Every day of my life was recorded in your book. Every moment was laid out before a single day had passed. How precious are your thoughts about me, O God. They cannot be numbered! I can’t even count them; they outnumber the grains of sand! And when I wake up, you are still with me!</p>
<cite>Psalms 139:13-18 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-snapwire-6945-1024x768.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ready to claim your salvation?]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/ready-to-claim-your-salvation</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/ready-to-claim-your-salvation</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[If you openly declare that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. For it is by believing in your heart that you are made right with God...]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>If you openly declare that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved. For it is by believing in your heart that you are made right with God, and it is by openly declaring your faith that you are saved. As the Scriptures tell us, “Anyone who trusts in him will never be disgraced.” Jew and Gentile are the same in this respect. They have the same Lord, who gives generously to all who call on him. For “Everyone who calls on the name of the Lord will be saved.”</p>
<cite> Romans 10:9-13 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
<p>
So, you want to know what it takes to be born again and join the kingdom of God? <a>Romans 10:9</a> gives the instructions and they are pretty simple. Just read out loud the prayer below and you will start your journey as a newborn babe in Christ. Make sure to check out my post on <a href="https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/resources-for-new-christians/">resources for new christians</a> for some tips on what you can do next!
</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p class="leading-loose italic font-semibold">
Father God, I believe with all my heart in Jesus Christ; the son of the living God. I believe God raised him from the dead and He is alive today. I confess with my mouth that Jesus Christ is the Lord of my life from this day. Through my faith in His name; the name of Jesus I receive remission of sins for my soul. I receive eternal life into my heart. Thank you, Lord, for saving my soul. Thank you for giving me a new life. I am born again, I am a child of God now. Thank you Lord. Amen!
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don’t copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God’s will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect.</p>
<cite> Romans 12:2 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-415571-1024x576.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Before you can love your neighbor]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/before-you-can-love-your-neighbor</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/before-you-can-love-your-neighbor</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The best way to learn to love yourself is to first start seeing yourself the way God sees you. Because the Word of God is truth!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>The man answered, “‘You must love the LORD your God with all your heart, all your soul, all your strength, and all your mind.’ And, ‘Love your neighbor as yourself.’”</p>
<p><cite>Luke 10:27</cite></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Before you can love your neighbor, you must love yourself. If you struggle with depression or other mental illness you might be thinking, how could I possibly love myself? I'm such a mess. But let me tell you, it's possible; and I don't mean by being selfish, fake, or conceded either. The best way to learn to love yourself is to first start seeing yourself the way God sees you. Because the Word of God is truth!</p>
<p>Even if you're not convinced of yourself, you can still rely on the truth that Jesus not only died for you, but he came back! He rose again on the 3rd day and sent someone to help you live. He went to sit at the right hand of God, and as he is now, so are we in the eyes of God. Greater is he that is in me, than he that is in the world. My righteousness was a gift from God. Not because I am the best person ever in the world, but because God saw me and had compassion. Because of his compassion, I have the right and ability to stand before God. And if God thinks I am great, then it must be so. For God so loved ME that he gave his only begotten son, that if only I was to believe his name, I WILL be given eternal life. Therefore, because I believe in the name of Jesus, I have eternal life! In Jesus' name. I am the head and not the tail. I am above and not beneath. My head is anointed with oil, my cup does overflow. The Lord hears his people when they pray. He loves those who are righteous, and because I believe, I have been made righteous in the sight of God. And if God loves me, then I can love myself.</p>
<p>Our strength is found in God. All of our infirmities are there to show us that we must rely on God. Because first I am weak then I am strong. His grace is sufficient, for his power is made perfect in weakness.
We have been given authority in this world. We've been given a purpose, and a mission, for how to continue living our lives as born-again children of God. We know that being born again, we are Kings and Queens.</p>
<p>Here are the scripture references if you don't believe me:</p>
<h6>1 Corinthians 15:3-6</h6>
I passed on to you what was most important and what had also been passed on to me. <b>Christ died for our sins</b>, just as the Scriptures said.  <b>He was buried, and he was raised from the dead on the third day</b>, just as the Scriptures said. He was seen by Peter and then by the Twelve. After that, he was seen by more than 500 of his followers at one time, most of whom are still alive, though some have died.
<h6>Romans 8:32-34</h6> Since he did not spare even his own Son but gave him up for us all, won’t he also give us everything else? Who dares accuse us whom God has chosen for his own? No one—for <b>God himself has given us right standing with himself</b>. Who then will condemn us? No one—<b>for Christ Jesus died for us and was raised to life for us, and he is sitting in the place of honor at God’s right hand, pleading for us.</b>
<h6>1 John 4:16-17 NKJV</h6> And we have known and believed the love that God has for us. God is love, and he who abides in love abides in God, and God in him. Love has been perfected among us in this: that we may have boldness in the day of judgment; <b>because as He is, so are we in this world</b>.
<h6>1 John 4:4 NKJV</h6> You are of God, little children, and have overcome them, because <b>He who is in you is greater than he who is in the world</b>.
<h6>Ephesians 2:8-9</h6> <b>God saved you by his grace when you believed</b>. And you can’t take credit for this; <b>it is a gift from God</b>. Salvation is not a reward for the good things we have done, so none of us can boast about it.
<h6>2 Corinthians 5:21</h6> For God made Christ, who never sinned, to be the offering for our sin, <b>so that we could be made right with God through Christ</b>.
<h6>John 3:16</h6> “For this is how God loved the world: He gave his one and only Son, so that everyone who believes in him will not perish but have eternal life.
<h6>Deuteronomy 28:13</h6> If you listen to these commands of the Lord your God that I am giving you today, and if you carefully obey them, <b>the Lord will make you the head and not the tail, and you will always be on top and never at the bottom.</b>
<h6>Psalm 23:5-6</h6> You prepare a feast for me in the presence of my enemies. <b>You honor me by anointing my head with oil</b>. <b>My cup overflows with blessings</b>. Surely your goodness and unfailing love will pursue me all the days of my life, and I will live in the house of the Lord forever.
<h6>Psalm 34:15</h6> The eyes of the Lord watch over those who do right; <b>his ears are open to their cries for help</b>. 
<h6>Romans 5:1</h6> Therefore, <b>since we have been made right in God’s sight by faith</b>, we have peace with God because of what Jesus Christ our Lord has done for us.
<h6>2 Corinthians 12:8-10</h6> Three different times I begged the Lord to take it away. Each time he said, “<b>My grace is all you need. My power works best in weakness</b>.” So now I am glad to boast about my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ can work through me. That’s why I take pleasure in my weaknesses, and in the insults, hardships, persecutions, and troubles that I suffer for Christ. <b>For when I am weak, then I am strong</b>.
<h6>Luke 10:19-20</h6> Look, <b>I have given you authority over all the power of the enemy</b>, and you can walk among snakes and scorpions and crush them. Nothing will injure you. But don’t rejoice because evil spirits obey you; rejoice because your names are registered in heaven.” 
<p><em><strong>All verses are from the NLT unless otherwise specified.</strong></em></p>
<blockquote>
But you are not like that, for you are a chosen people. You are royal priests, a holy nation, God’s very own possession. As a result, you can show others the goodness of God, for he called you out of the darkness into his wonderful light.
<cite>1 Peter 2:9 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-pixabay-255441-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Crying out to God]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/crying-out-to-god</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/crying-out-to-god</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I don't know why I feel like I must always act strong when I'm with God. It doesn't make sense, because He already knows my heart and my thoughts ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
I feel like sometimes I don't know how to cry out to God. Not because I think he's doesn't hear me, but because I just feel like a whiny little child. I don't know why I feel like I must always act strong when I'm with God. It doesn't make sense, because He already knows my heart and my thoughts (<a>Psalm 139:1-2</a>), so why do I think I can't talk about it with Him?
</p>
<p>
This is one reason why I truly admire David. He would cry out to God for everything! If he sinned, he'd confess and beg forgiveness without caring how others perceived him (<a>2 Samuel 12:13-17</a>). In times of difficulty, he'd cry out to God and ask him, Lord, like seriously, why is this happening to me? But even amid all his feelings, of the world around him being against him, he could always turn to God and say, even though everyone says you're no good, I know you bring joy and peace. You will deliver me! (Psalm 10 and more)
</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-luis-fernandes-2422854-1024x680.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resources for New Christians]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/resources-for-new-christians</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/resources-for-new-christians</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ As a new believer, it can feel overwhelming trying to figure out what to do to get as close to God as the people in the faith you admire seem to be. Here are just a few places to start if you are currently in that situation.  ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
You’ve confessed Jesus as your Lord and savior as stated in <a>Romans 10:9</a>, now what? As a new believer, it can feel overwhelming trying to figure out what to do to get as close to God as the people in the faith you admire seem to be. Here are just a few places to start if you are currently in that situation. 
</p>
<h5>1. The Bible</h5>
<p>
I recommend finding the translation that works best for you. King James Version (KJV), and New King James Version (NKJV) were too hard for me to grasp easily, so I used the New International Version (NIV) for a while before I found the New Living Translation (NLT); which I find very easy to read and understand on the first read. I enjoyed the Message version (MSG) as well, but that one was a bit harder to reference since it often combined verses into paragraphs. Amplified Classic version (AMPC) gives a lot of extra details, but I get distracted easily if I'm using it to get through the Bible. When studying, I always compare between versions, usually NLT, KJV, NKJ, and AMPC. I would also recommend investing in a Study Bible.
</p>
<h5>2. Pastor and/or Church Leaders</h5>
<p>
I think reaching out to your pastor or church leaders is a great next step. They should have a lot more experience and understanding to share and they can point you to certain passages to read and meditate on. A reputable pastor, elder, or leader will also be able to provide great Godly advice on how to advance in your faith walk.
</p>
<h5>3. Christian Websites</h5>
<p>
One of my favorite places to go when I have Bible related questions is <a href="http://gotquestions.com/">gotquestions.com</a>. I think they do a great job of answering questions according to the Bible without taking verses out of context. They also have multiple scriptural verses to back up their answers. Of course, there are many other sources that can be used. Many pastors and churches have written Bible studies on topics you may be struggling with that can be found with just a web search.
</p>
<h5>4. YouTube, Podcasts and Christian Influencers</h5>
<p>
YouTube is a great place to watch sermons which can really help in broadening your understanding and at the same time see that the fundamentals of Christianity can be found in many churches (as it should). The different points of view and understandings are great for reaching different types of audiences, you never know whose explanation will finally give you that revelation you were lacking on a certain verse/section. Some of the people and churches I’ve enjoyed listening to are: Pastor Charles Stanley from In Touch Ministries, Pastor Chris Oyakhilome from Christ Embassy, Apostle Joshua Selman, Jackie Hill Perry, Focus on the Family, and The Bible Project.
</p>
<p>
Have any resources you find helpful? Share them in the comments down below and let’s start a conversation!
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>'Don’t let anyone think less of you because you are young. Be an example to all believers in what you say, in the way you live, in your love, your faith, and your purity. '</p>
<cite>1 Timothy 4:12</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-rodnae-productions-5875303-1-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Renewal of the Mind]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/renewal-of-the-mind</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/renewal-of-the-mind</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ Even when I feel a little depressed or sad, I still know the truth God has told me about my situation and can work to dismiss the lies the devil wants to make me believe. ]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/html">
As someone who has been through severe depression, I know how hard the battle is to see pass those negative thoughts the devil tries to feed us as truth. There was a point where walking through a dark tunnel seemed like all life had in store for me. But really, I had unpacked my bags there and decided that’s where I was meant to be. Besides, walking through the tunnel to see if there really was a light at the end seemed like too much work. I was content with just dying in that darkness. But when I gave my life to Christ, He showed me that I didn’t have to stay there. In fact, I could not stay there! So, I packed the important stuff, and started my journey through the tunnel with Jesus Christ as my flashlight.
</p>
<p>
Negative thoughts were something that I had to constantly fight off as I started to overcome my depression. <a>Romans 12:2 NLT</a> says “Don’t copy the behavior and customs of this world, but let God transform you into a new person by changing the way you think. Then you will learn to know God’s will for you, which is good and pleasing and perfect”. I still struggle every now and then, but now I have a tool box of scriptures I can counter my negative thoughts with. So even when I feel a little depressed or sad, I still know the truth God has told me about my situation and can work to dismiss the lies the devil wants to make me believe.
</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>
When I think: <b>I’m not good enough</b> <br/>
I declare: <b>'You are of God</b>, little children, and have overcome them, because <b>He who is in you is greater than he who is in the world</b>. ' <br />
<a>1 John 4:4 NKJV</a>
</p>
<p>
When I think: <b>No one loves me </b> <br/>
I declare: And I am convinced <b>that nothing can ever separate us from God’s love.</b> Neither death nor life, neither angels nor demons, neither our fears for today nor our worries about tomorrow—not even the powers of hell can separate us from God’s love. No power in the sky above or in the earth below—indeed, nothing in all creation will ever be able to separate us from the love of God that is revealed in Christ Jesus our Lord. <br />
<a>Romans 8:38-39 NLT</a>
</p>
<p>
When I think: <b>I’m a failure</b><br/>
I declare: 'For I can do everything through Christ, who gives me strength. ' <br />
<a>Philippians 4:13 NLT</a>
</p>
<p>
When I think: <b>What if xyz doesn’t work out</b><br />
I declare: '“<b>So don’t worry about tomorrow, for tomorrow will bring its own worries. Today’s trouble is enough for today.</b> These things dominate the thoughts of unbelievers, but your heavenly Father already knows all your needs. Seek the Kingdom of God. above all else, and live righteously, and he will give you everything you need.'  <br />
<a>Matthew 6:32-34 NLT</a>
</p>
<p>
When I think: <b>I’m better off dead</b><br />
I declare: 'I passed on to you what was most important and what had also been passed on to me.  <b>Christ died for our sins</b>, just as the Scriptures said. He was buried, and he was raised from the dead on the third day, just as the Scriptures said. ' <br />
<a>1 Corinthians 15:3-4 NLT</a>
</p>
<p>
When I think: <b>Life isn’t worth it</b><br />
I declare: 'For I know the plans I have for you,” says the Lord. “They are plans for good and not for disaster, to give you a future and a hope. In those days when you pray, I will listen. '. <br />
<a>Jeremiah 29:11-12</a>
</p>
<p>
Do you have any thoughts that you’re trying to overcome? Or scripture that help you in difficult times? Do you have anything you want to hear me talk about in the future? Share them down in the comments!
</p>
<blockquote>
<p> And now, dear brothers and sisters, one final thing. Fix your thoughts on what is true, and honorable, and right, and pure, and lovely, and admirable. Think about things that are excellent and worthy of praise.</p>
<cite>Philippians 4:8 NLT</cite>
</blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-fillipe-gomes-5471399-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I want you to know]]></title>
            <link>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-want-you-to-know</link>
            <guid>https://overcomewithchrist.com/posts/i-want-you-to-know</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I want you to know that Jesus loves you. I'm not talking about a superficial love either.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>
That Jesus loves you. I'm not talking about a superficial love either. While you were yet in your mother's womb, the Lord knew you and loved you (<a>Jeremiah 1:5</a>). He's counted the hairs on your head (<a>Luke 12:7</a>), and he has great plans for you. Plans to prosper you, and give you a hope and a future (<a>Jeremiah 29:11</a>). If you didn't know this, then I want you to know this. I want you to take it in. I want you to understand this.
</p>
<p>
Before you could do anything to prove yourself (<a>Romans 5:8</a>), God said you were enough. He showed this by sending his son, in human flesh, who did nothing wrong, to be sin for you and make you righteous (<a>2 Corinth 5:21</a>). He gave you an advocate who will stand for you when you mess up (<a>1 John 2:1</a>), and a comforter to walk with you and guide you in every situation so you may have peace (<a>John 14:26-27</a>).
</p>
<p>
All he asks in return is that you acknowledge Him and confess that He is your Lord and savior (<a>Romans 10:9</a>). Because His mercy is what saves you and all you need to complete it is faith (<a>Ephesians 2:8-9</a>). And once you understand that God's love is already the highest it can be and can't be lessened or increased by what you do, then you will be set free (<a>Ephesians 3:18-19</a>).
</p>
<p>
Once you realize this, I hope you'll be willing to give your life back to God, the creator of all the heavens and the earth (<a>Isaiah 40:28-31</a>).
</p>
<blockquote>
<p>
If you openly declare that Jesus is Lord and believe in your heart that God raised him from the dead, you will be saved.
</p>
<cite>
Romans 10:9 NLT
</cite>
</blockquote>]]></content:encoded>
            <enclosure url="https://res.cloudinary.com/dn7ubiddg/image/upload/v1685671919/blog/pexels-ylanite-koppens-810036-1024x682.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg"/>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>